<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reviews on The Seattle Review of Books</title>
    <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reviews on The Seattle Review of Books</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All content ©{ year } the Seattle Review of Books, and respective authors.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 12:01:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;...the goddamn Great American Landscaping Novel&#34;</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-goddamn-great-american-landscaping-novel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 12:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-goddamn-great-american-landscaping-novel/</guid>
      <description>Novels are economic artifacts. Some of the greatest novels of all time - books by Dickens, Steinbeck, and Allison come immediately to mind -were lauded because the authors wrote beautifully and knowingly about the lives of poor people. But walk around a bookstore reading dust jackets today and you&amp;rsquo;ll see that an overwhelming majority of the novels that land on bestseller lists are about the middle class and the upper middle class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take this sentence, for example</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/take-this-sentence-for-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 12:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/take-this-sentence-for-example/</guid>
      <description>Good writing elicits a feeling that the words on the page were always meant to be. Like a film, say, where you don&amp;rsquo;t see the thousands of hours and hundreds of people sweating over the details to make a product that feels effortless when projected. Both the writing and film share a secret: they are more than the sum of their parts, but they are made of only of their parts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying to make sense of the border</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/trying-to-make-sense-of-the-border/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/trying-to-make-sense-of-the-border/</guid>
      <description>When I was a college student in San Diego, I worked part-time at the Natural History Museum doing a variety of jobs. I was a zoology major and was once invited to join the herpetologist and his student assistants in the field. We drove over the mountains and dropped into the desert near the border. I was the only brown person in the car, and when a border patrol helicopter whirred overhead, one of the assistants yelled, with mock urgency, “Hide Donna!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Would you rather</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/would-you-rather/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 11:55:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/would-you-rather/</guid>
      <description>Visit any bookstore and you&amp;rsquo;ll see that a whole spectrum of once-viable books are no longer considered desirable. It&amp;rsquo;s virtually impossible, for instance, to give away a set of old encyclopedias. The &amp;ldquo;…for Dummies&amp;rdquo; series of books about outdated computer programs are literally not worth the paper and ink they&amp;rsquo;re printed on. And very few people have any interest in antique buying guides.
Another book that seems to be falling out of favor is the humble joke book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A wolf at the door</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-wolf-at-the-door/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-wolf-at-the-door/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I am less horrible than I could be&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; I’ve never set a house on fire&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;never thrown a firstborn off a bridge still my whole life I answered every cry for help with a pour&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;with a turning away&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;I’ve given this coldness many names&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;thinking if it had a name it would have a solution&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;thinking if I called a wolf a wolf I might dull its fangs&amp;rdquo; — Kaveh Akbar, “Calling a Wolf a Wolf (Inpatient)” “The first step in solving a problem is to recognize that it does exist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never forget, never forgive</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/never-forget-never-forgive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 12:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/never-forget-never-forgive/</guid>
      <description>The natural state of humanity is to acknowledge tragedy, to honor it, and then to move on. We forget the dead, we can&amp;rsquo;t remember what pain felt like in the exact moment that we realized something horrible had happened. This is a survival mechanism; if we never physically stopped feeling the immediate hurt of heartbreak and loss, we would not live for very long. The pain has to fade; the memory has to dissolve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The plumber who went to an art museum (and other American heroes)</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-plumber-who-went-to-an-art-museum-and-other-american-heroes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-plumber-who-went-to-an-art-museum-and-other-american-heroes/</guid>
      <description>In the winter of 1897, a New York City plumber taking a break from a job on Fifth Avenue did something that went viral (or at least the late nineteenth century equivalent). He walked into the Metropolitan Museum of Art to check out the exhibitions and was promptly asked to leave. The reason? His dirty overalls were deemed offensive to the sensibilities of this refined cultural space.
Initially reported in the New York Times, the incident made headlines across the country, sparking vigorous debate about the relationship between the museum and the working classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soldiering on</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/soldiering-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 11:47:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/soldiering-on/</guid>
      <description>Dunkirk, Christopher Nolan&amp;rsquo;s World War II film, is a brilliant technical achievement. Made using mostly practical special effects, and told through an ambitious three-tier story that collapses three different timelines into a single climactic battle, the movie was one of the most remarkable cinematic achievements of 2017.
I watched Dunkirk at the Cinerama on opening weekend, and I appreciated both the film&amp;rsquo;s technical mastery and the pure emotion behind it. But I&amp;rsquo;m embarrassed to admit that for much of the film&amp;rsquo;s runtime, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t tell what the hell was going on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Picking up the pencil</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/picking-up-the-pencil/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/picking-up-the-pencil/</guid>
      <description>![](/webhook-uploads/1520314169250/ArtistsWay%2001.png)
![](/webhook-uploads/1520314180211/ArtistsWay%2002.png)
![](/webhook-uploads/1520314188991/ArtistsWay%2003.png)
![](/webhook-uploads/1520314200659/ArtistsWay%2004.png)
![](/webhook-uploads/1520314217335/ArtistsWay%2005.png)
![](/webhook-uploads/1520314227479/ArtistsWay%2006.png)
![](/webhook-uploads/1520314238186/ArtistsWay%2007.png)
![](/webhook-uploads/1520314246487/ArtistsWay%2008.png)
![](/webhook-uploads/1520314283432/ArtistsWay%2009.png)
![](/webhook-uploads/1520314304473/ArtistsWay%2010.png)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Land of promise</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/land-of-promise/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 13:12:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/land-of-promise/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;What we were heading toward,&amp;rdquo; Seattle writer Natalie Singer writes at the beginning of her new memoir…
…was bigger than a natural, perfect family. In that plane, over the next six hours, I would cross over into what I hoped would be my own version of freedom. By the time the plane touched down at the San Jose International Airport, I would be unburdened of the pressures of my old high school, the weight of family secrets that burned like a brand, and the loneliness of my existence in the nowhere of the North.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Let us be part of the change&#34;</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/let-us-be-part-of-the-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/let-us-be-part-of-the-change/</guid>
      <description>There’s an iconic photograph of the Philippine People Power Revolution of February 1986 that ousted Ferdinand Marcos: several men perch atop light poles, while beneath them a sea of people swells on Epifanio de los Santos Avenue (EDSA), a Coca-Cola sign — that symbol of American enterprise — in the distance. Over three days, more than two million citizens mobilized in spontaneous opposition to the US-supported dictator. Declining the advice of one of his generals to fire upon the people, Marcos fled the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Show the backlist some love!</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/show-the-backlist-some-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/show-the-backlist-some-love/</guid>
      <description>For the first month of the year, those interested in children’s literature speculate frantically about which books will win the American Library Association’s book awards. And when the winners are announced, sales go up. Before Kelly Barnhill’s The Girl Who Drank the Moon received the 2017 Newbery Medal, its sales were 17,484. After it won, the number shot up to 56,653 — a 324% shift. The same goes for the year-end lists produced by organizations and book lovers to promote the “best” children’s or young adult books published that year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The beautiful strange</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-beautiful-strange/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-beautiful-strange/</guid>
      <description>A keening moan in the night that is somehow both human and animal. An artist who makes a chrysalis sculpture that becomes the molted husk of her own transformation. A merciless city-state grafting living animal and machine parts to its prisoners. An historian of a lost culture who infects himself with plant spores in pursuit of the truth. This is the teeming, constantly transforming world of the New Weird. This small, experimental and hybrid genre planted its flag at the intersection between fantasy, horror, sci-fi, and supernatural two decades ago and continues to cultivate that fertile territory today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Room for everything</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/room-for-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 12:01:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/room-for-everything/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a story you&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard: in a strange world of dragons and heroes, a bratty young heir to a great fortune is about to enter an arranged marriage with a young woman he&amp;rsquo;s never met. Published in January, Chandler Klang Smith&amp;rsquo;s second novel The Sky Is Yours takes that simple hero narrative and plasters it over with…well, everything.
The Sky Is Yours is what I&amp;rsquo;ve come to describe as an &amp;lsquo;everything novel,&amp;rsquo; by which I mean it&amp;rsquo;s one of those huge, overstuffed tomes that seems to contain every stray thought the author&amp;rsquo;s mind entertained over the course of the writing of the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In a virtual world, trolls are real</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/in-a-virtual-world-trolls-are-real/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 12:16:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/in-a-virtual-world-trolls-are-real/</guid>
      <description>In 2008 I opened a Twitter account. I was driving from Seattle to Chicago with two friends for a social media conference; we used Twitter to communicate our location, to meet strangers along the way, to get ideas about where to stop and what to do once we’d stopped there. A friend joined Twitter while I was on the road. He’d been following my 140-character-count updates for much of the journey, but he really wanted to tweet back: It was essential I not miss a particular roadside attraction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be prepared</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/be-prepared/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 11:56:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/be-prepared/</guid>
      <description>Outdoorsiness is having a moment. All of a sudden, popular culture is obsessed with people (particularly young people) fending for themselves in the wild. In comics like Lumberjanes, in fiction for young readers like Arlo Finch in the Valley of Fire, in novels like My Absolute Darling, in films like The Mountain Between Us, characters are using quick wits and thoughtful preparation to survive in the woods without any of the technological advances we take for granted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It all works out, in theory</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/it-all-works-out-in-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/it-all-works-out-in-theory/</guid>
      <description>How do you enter the conversation among generations of Continental philosophers? Learn the lingo — and bring a bodyguard. In The Seventh Function of Language, Laurent Binet depicts the big names in 1980s literary theory — Jacques Derrida, Michel Foucault, Julia Kristeva, Bernard-Henri Lévy — as hedonistic, ego-driven monsters who would not hesitate to kill or maim to demonstrate their intellectual superiority. Binet’s novel weaponizes literary theory, a central conceit that brings to mind the Monty Python skit “The funniest joke in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dark side of the sun</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-dark-side-of-the-sun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 11:55:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-dark-side-of-the-sun/</guid>
      <description>Seattle author Ross McMeekin is probably best known as the founder and editor of Spartan, the minimalist literary journal. Spartan has, over the course of a few years, become one of the more influential literary forces in the Seattle area; it’s rare to find a group reading in the city, for example, that does not include a Spartan author on the bill.
So when McMeekin announced that his debut novel would be published by Skyhorse in February of 2018, most local folks assumed that The Hummingbirds would be something, well, Spartan — that is to say: minimalist, and literary, and stripped-down, and interested in furthering the Seattle aesthetic McMeekin has promoted over the course of his career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too complicated to feel</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/too-complicated-to-feel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/too-complicated-to-feel/</guid>
      <description>There is a specific beauty to the movements of a mind that has consciously taught itself to reroute around its own weaknesses, that has learned to take unexpected backroads through the landscapes it feels least equipped to understand. About half a decade ago, Ben Blum and I crossed paths in Seattle, and I recognized in him a very particular sort of kinship. We were both presenting for Washington Ensemble Theater’s Sixpack Series, a wildly irreverent literary reading that gives genre-spanning creatives a theme (in this case, ”too bored for the lord”), a month to prep, and twenty completely open minutes on stage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ave Marías</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/ave-mar%C3%ADas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 13:03:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/ave-mar%C3%ADas/</guid>
      <description>Juarez, Mexico is frequently referred to as the most dangerous place in the world. A second’s worth of Googling will uncover terms like “Murder Valley” and news stories titled “Who Is Killing the Women of Juarez?” It is a city that is universally known for violence and death, and that reputation serves many purposes. The drug cartels that keep the city in a grip of fear have redefined the city of Juarez, transformed the world’s perception of the city into a war zone, a place where innocent victims die with startling regularity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How bad is it?</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/how-bad-is-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 11:59:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/how-bad-is-it/</guid>
      <description>On Saturday, thousands of women’s march protesters made downtown Seattle feel as vibrant and alive as it does on any weekday. You could tell who the protesters were by their signs, by their pink knit hats, by the spontaneous chants that joyfully erupted on street corners and in public spaces.
Much of the media failed to acknowledge the hundred thousand protesters who gathered peacefully at Cal Anderson Park and marched down to Seattle Center, but if you were on the street, these protesters were impossible to ignore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seattle, naturally</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/seattle-naturally/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 11:55:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/seattle-naturally/</guid>
      <description>This might sound misanthropic, but it’s true: Some of the best nature writing that I’ve ever read is about cities. Edward Abbey — the shaggy, problematic voice of 1970s environmental activism — wrote fondly about New York City in such a way that you’d want to divide your time, as he did, between the city and the desert. He embraced the metropolis and celebrated its artificiality even as he cautiously guarded the natural peace of the desert, and he saw no hypocrisy in loving both.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alphabetical order</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/alphabetical-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 11:52:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/alphabetical-order/</guid>
      <description>When mystery author Sue Grafton died at the end of December, she famously left her Alphabet Series of mysteries unfinished. The summer of 2017 saw the publication of the penultimate volume in the series — Y Is for Yesterday — and Grafton hadn’t even started writing Z Is for Zero, which she had always referred to as her final book. When announcing Grafton’s death, her daughter wrote that the series will remain unfinished: “As far as we in the family are concerned, the alphabet now ends at Y.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Words written in anger, words written in ink</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/words-written-in-anger-words-written-in-ink/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/words-written-in-anger-words-written-in-ink/</guid>
      <description>Ta-Nehisi Coates&#39;s We Were Eight Years in Power is a pensive, complex book. Interlacing memoir and essay, Coates reports on America after Barack Obama&#39;s presidency with nuance and emotional weight. This the best work I have read from him.
And yet _Eight Years in Power_ has been attacked by many online as agitprop with biblical pretensions that aids and abets Nazism. When Coates analyzes the symbolism of Barack Obama’s success to a black America that gave him 94 percent of their vote, Dan McLaughlin says Coates is [one with Richard Spencer](http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A fairy tale of New York</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-fairy-tale-of-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 12:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-fairy-tale-of-new-york/</guid>
      <description>Pluta, the teenager at the heart of Seattle novelist Anca Szilágyi’s debut Daughters of the Air, has all the makings of a fairy tale protagonist. Her life seems cursed: Her father disappears. She wanders into the world alone, meeting monsters. She uncovers her own hidden power. Love pushes her onward, but always seems to be just out of reach.
But this isn’t a fairy tale; it’s fiction, but it feels as real and as insistent as the vein pulsing just over your right eye.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mourning pause</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-mourning-pause/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-mourning-pause/</guid>
      <description>Our manic relationship to memoir has already circled through many shame spirals in this reality-hungry culture, and the dog memoir genre — from the stirring Hachikoto books to the feel-good Marley and Me franchise — is so oversaturated that every purchase comes with complimentary eye-rolls. Jill Abramson, of The New York Times, was slaughtered in reviews of The Puppy Diaries, partially because she expressed her fantasy of sharing monumental bylines with her canine partner, Scout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biden&#39;s time</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/bidens-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 11:55:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/bidens-time/</guid>
      <description>I’ll fight to the grave on this: Joe Biden was one of the most effective vice presidents in the history of the United States.
It’s hard to recall now, but in 2008 Biden’s experience and genial demeanor afforded a small but important subset of white American voters with the confidence to vote for the first black president. Once in office, though, Biden transformed into a very different figure than Token White Grandpa: he became the Crazy Uncle of the White House, the figure who’s prone to blurting out what everyone else was thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reclaiming the story of women&#39;s bodies</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/reclaiming-the-story-of-womens-bodies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/reclaiming-the-story-of-womens-bodies/</guid>
      <description>As the title of Carmen Maria Machado’s debut collection suggests, the stories in Her Body and Other Parties are about women’s lives and bodies, which means that, above all, men must read them.
The blurbs on the book are numerous and rightfully ecstatic from writers of no small repute, and it’s a good sign that half of the jacket endorsements come from male writers. Not that their opinions matter more than the notable women who also praised the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking around Seattle with Jane Jacobs</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/walking-around-seattle-with-jane-jacobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 11:54:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/walking-around-seattle-with-jane-jacobs/</guid>
      <description>![](/webhook-uploads/1510622110538/IMG_3436.JPG)
A city never looks so noble, or so full of potential, as when you’re viewing it through Jane Jacobs’s eyes. For the last week or so, I’ve been walking through Seattle while listening to an audio recording of the 50th anniversary edition of Jane Jacobs’s The Death and Life of American Cities. It’s an experience I’d recommend to anyone.
When you’re walking in downtown Seattle, Jacobs becomes your personal tour guide, pointing out areas (like the always-vibrant stretch of Pike and Pine north of Broadway) where pedestrians activate and enliven a space through work and play, and critiquing other areas (like the weird airy mall at 6th Ave &amp;amp; Union) that seem to push humans away with a vague sense of dread and alienation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowing and doing and the passive sin of hipster privilege</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/knowing-and-doing-and-the-passive-sin-of-hipster-privilege/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 11:55:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/knowing-and-doing-and-the-passive-sin-of-hipster-privilege/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, actor Charlene Yi told a story about comedian David Cross. She recalled on social media that the first time she met Cross, a decade ago, he said several racist comments to her. Yi was offended, but Cross at that time was a popular celebrity, and she felt too powerless to respond.
Cross responded by saying “I do not remember it like she remembers it,” and that “I am NOT accusing Charlene of lying and I’m truly sorry if I hurt her,” but he concludes “I am not a racist nor a bully and loathe them in real life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A city of one</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-city-of-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 13:03:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-city-of-one/</guid>
      <description>You’ve seen these kinds of juxtapositions before: someone will place a photograph of a specific location from a century ago up against a contemporary photograph. Usually, the intent is to make a reader shake their head and wonder about the horrible price of progress: a beautiful old Victorian home in the “before” frame has given way to an ugly strip mall in the “after,” for instance. A field becomes a gas station.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White ignorance</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/white-ignorance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 09:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/white-ignorance/</guid>
      <description>It is incredibly difficult to explain one’s own ignorance to someone else.
At last night’s Reading Through It book group at Third Place Books Seward Park, many of us used the phrase “punched in the gut” to describe Carol Anderson’s brilliant White Rage: The Unspoken Truth of Our Racial Divide. The book, which documents the institutional history of white supremacy of the United States, lays out the many ways white America has systematically made even existing while being black an illegal act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventures in the third dimension</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/adventures-in-the-third-dimension/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 12:24:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/adventures-in-the-third-dimension/</guid>
      <description>Ever since the dawn of comics, cartoonists have tried to break free from the bounds of the page. Those cartoonists have discovered that comics grant them mastery over two dimensions, but they are powerless in the third dimension: you can do anything with width and height in comics, but it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to add depth.
Read any comic and you’ll find evidence of cartoonists pushing back against this fundamental limitation. You’ll find figures bursting free from the constricting lines of the panel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going steady</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/going-steady/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 12:15:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/going-steady/</guid>
      <description>“I have a boyfriend.”
The main character in Tara Atkinson’s new novella Boyfriends says that sentence multiple times, and it’s not a statement of ownership, or an appreciation of a fact. Instead, she uses the sentence as a talisman to ward off other guys when they get creepy, when they try to make a move on her.
It’s not enough that she’s simply not interested in the men. She has to announce that she “belongs” to another man before they’ll leave her alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The good old days aren&#39;t what they used to be</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-good-old-days-arent-what-they-used-to-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 11:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-good-old-days-arent-what-they-used-to-be/</guid>
      <description>Here are some words I never thought I would apply to a Noam Chomsky book: shallow, flimsy, ill-considered, dumb, and badly written.
And yet, here we are.
Requiem for the American Dream: The 10 Principles of Concentration of Wealth &amp;amp; Power, the October selection of the Reading Through It Book Club, is a bad book. Requiem is basically a transcription of a documentary by the same name — Chomsky’s “final, long-form documentary interviews,” according to the jacket copy — and it fails on just about every conceivable level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Among the ruins</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/among-the-ruins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/among-the-ruins/</guid>
      <description>As a teenager, I developed an obsession with estate sales. I partially attribute this fascination to growing up not knowing my father. I have never met anyone from his side of the family. For a long time, I felt like a half-formed thing. I often still do. I would wander through dusty basements that smelled of Pine Sol and mothballs, turning over wristwatches and ashtrays in my hands, using the mementos of strangers to construct images of the family I never knew.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Born Again </title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/born-again-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 12:19:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/born-again-/</guid>
      <description>“There is a Korean belief that you are born/the parent of the one you hurt most,” writes EJ Koh in her debut poetry collection A Lesser Love. . It’s such a perfect idea that it hurts your heart just to think about it.
There’s a justice to the thought of being entirely responsible for the person you will wrong most in this world. They wake you every night, squalling and wordless and purely filled with rage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The language of justice</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-language-of-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-language-of-justice/</guid>
      <description>There is a language of rape. The words differ depending on who’s speaking. There are the words used by the perpetrators. There are the words by the deniers and the words by the blamers. There are the words by the victims when they can manage to speak them. While all these words are part of the stories in M. Evelina Galang’s Lolas’ House: Filipino Women Living With War, it is the victims’ words that Galang rightly honors, giving them the pages they deserve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We built this city</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/we-built-this-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 11:56:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/we-built-this-city/</guid>
      <description>Seattle writer Charles R. Wolfe’s recent book Seeing the Better City: How to Explore, Observe, and Improve Urban Space argues that city-dwellers are more than just passive participants in the urban experience. Wolfe contends that it is everyone’s job to investigate cities, to note changes in neighborhoods, to imagine ways that the city might be improved, to record the interaction between humans and their environment.
In order to facilitate active involvement with cities, Wolfe encourages his readers to keep what he calls “urban diaries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drawn from felt</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/drawn-from-felt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/drawn-from-felt/</guid>
      <description>![](/webhook-uploads/1505708688607/froh-1.jpg)
![](/webhook-uploads/1505709712938/froh-2.jpg)
![](/webhook-uploads/1505923059367/froh-3.jpg)
![](/webhook-uploads/1505708725599/froh-4.jpg)
![](/webhook-uploads/1505708735211/froh-5.jpg)
![](/webhook-uploads/1505708744288/froh-6.jpg)
![](/webhook-uploads/1505708752722/froh-7.jpg)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The line between &#34;you&#34; and &#34;me&#34;</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-line-between-you-and-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-line-between-you-and-me/</guid>
      <description>It is a towering, temporary construct in the middle of publisher Mount Analogue’s Pioneer Square gallery/storefront. It resembles a child’s blanket fort: some white sheets hanging from the ceiling, adorned with glittering strands of tinsel and crinkled-up tinfoil and spritzes of brightly colored artificial flowers. The structure is surrounded by Mount Analogue’s usual décor — handmade books and ceramic cigarette packs and gloves with weird phrases sewn into them — and a large collection of potted plants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explaining the inexplicable</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/explaining-the-inexplicable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 11:57:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/explaining-the-inexplicable/</guid>
      <description>At the end of a recent vacation, I decided to buy Hillary Clinton’s new election memoir, What Happened, at an airport bookstore. One bookstore didn’t have it in stock. I went to the NBC-branded shop near my gate and at first I couldn’t find a copy there, either. Finally, I found the book: it was high up on the bestseller wall, but someone had turned the display copy upside-down, in effigy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The transmogrification of Kesha Rose Sebert</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-transmogrification-of-kesha-rose-sebert/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 11:48:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-transmogrification-of-kesha-rose-sebert/</guid>
      <description>Kesha had to know that her first album in five years, Rainbow, would be examined as a personal statement. This isn’t a rarity in modern pop music — reviewers scour Taylor Swift’s albums, say, for evidence of autobiographical details about her recent relationships —but Kesha has been under increased scrutiny since the release of Warrior in 2012.
It’s a long, sad story. In 2014, Kesha sued her producer, who works under the name Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Song of the South</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/song-of-the-south/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 11:59:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/song-of-the-south/</guid>
      <description>I do not recommend that writers read Joan Didion’s latest book, South and West, unless they have a very strong ego. Subtitled From a Notebook, South is a published version of Didion’s notes that she compiled during a 1970s trip to southern states. She never shaped the notes into an essay or a collection, and she undoubtedly never intended her notes to be published.
And here’s where the potential bruised ego comes in for writers who read this book: Joan Didion’s goddamned notes are more compelling, more finely wrought, than most writers’ finished products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The end of the world, again</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-end-of-the-world-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 12:22:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-end-of-the-world-again/</guid>
      <description>Every dystopia needs a gimmick — some hook to distinguish it from the ever-expanding constellation of literary post-apocalypses. Seattle writer Jennie Melamed’s Gather the Daughters is a dystopian novel that remixes several pre-existing gimmicks into one. Melamed’s influences are right there in a blurb on the front cover of the book, as written by Helene Wecker, who calls it “An heir to the creations of Margaret Atwood and Shirley Jackson.” That’s about as succinct an observation as you can fit in a front-cover blurb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why can&#39;t literature deal with climate change?</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/why-cant-literature-deal-with-climate-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/why-cant-literature-deal-with-climate-change/</guid>
      <description>In March of 1979, Amitav Ghosh witnessed a bizarre storm in Delhi, India. The sky darkened, unseasonable rain squalls turned to hail, and a funnel-shaped whirlwind appeared. Ghosh ran for cover. He emerged to find buses overturned, scooters wedged in trees, and walls torn from buildings. The lethal event, which killed at least 30 people, was so rare that newspapers didn’t correctly identify it for two days — a tornado, the first in the region’s recorded history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awkward teenage poetry as a force for good</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/awkward-teenage-poetry-as-a-force-for-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 12:26:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/awkward-teenage-poetry-as-a-force-for-good/</guid>
      <description>We’ve all got those notebook pages crammed full of bad poetry skulking somewhere around in our pasts, don’t we? I know I tried to communicate the wretched angst and hormonal discomfort of my teen years in poetry. I filled page after page of three-hole-punched notebook paper with awful, unrhymed poems, in a desperate attempt to communicate the hell of my perfectly safe and privileged adolescence to the world. Thankfully, I destroyed all those papers many years ago, but sometimes I can still summon a line to mind, and it invariably makes me cringe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The devil eats his own tail</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-devil-eats-his-own-tail/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 10:26:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-devil-eats-his-own-tail/</guid>
      <description>Some smartass on Twitter pointed out that the Trump presidency is the first one where the American people, and not the president, will age twenty years over a single term of office. Time is flowing in an incredibly weird way these days. Days sometimes feel like minutes, but weeks feel like months. And months feel like decades.
So I want you to cast your memory waaaaaaaaaayyyyyy back to the distant past of February 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unstacking the deck</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/unstacking-the-deck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/unstacking-the-deck/</guid>
      <description>When I called my Dad to tell him I had less than $100 in my bank account, he was understandably frustrated. Here he was subsidizing his son’s second internship in Washington DC — an unpaid one at that. He never had to intern in the 1980s. He spent his summers working in the back of kitchens, graduated from college and then got a middle-class job. He most likely anticipated that I would follow a similar order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation is not kale</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/translation-is-not-kale/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/translation-is-not-kale/</guid>
      <description>August 2017 marks the fourth year running for [Women in Translation Month](https://womenintranslation.com). The project was launched in 2014 by [Meytal Radzinski](https://literarytranslators.wordpress.com/2016/07/25/women-in-translation-an-interview-witth-meytal-radzinski/), a scholar and passionate reader of non-English literature, to encourage discussion about the incredible disparity in publication of translated works by women vs. men. The skew line is, painfully but not surprisingly, even steeper than for published writing overall.
It&#39;s an urgent issue, enough to keep the WIT project expanding to an ever-broader group of participants around the world — writers, translators, readers, critics — and to drive the inauguration of the new [Warwick Prize for Women in Translation](http://www2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unreal estate</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/unreal-estate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 11:41:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/unreal-estate/</guid>
      <description>Authors love to write haunted house novels because they’re all symbolism, and symbolism is fun to write. Why labor over a Cheeveresque, subtle examination of a typically unhappy suburban family when you can just have blood literally pouring from the walls of their home? The haunted house story combines America’s top three love affairs — real estate, dysfunctional families, and karmic retribution — into one sloppy orgy.
But the problem with haunted house stories is that they’ve been done so often that it’s almost impossible to add something new to the form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Second Coming</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-second-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 12:16:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-second-coming/</guid>
      <description>Almost exactly four years ago, I reviewed Seattle author Richard Chiem’s short story collection You Private Person. I request that you don’t look up the review. It’s not bad, exactly, but I clearly didn’t understand the book very well. I blabbed for a while, failed to find a point, and then concluded the review having said exactly nothing. (Pro tip: when a reviewer opens a piece raving about the beauty of an author’s sentences, that reviewer is probably pushing up against a deadline and can’t figure out what else to say.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We the poems</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/we-the-poems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 12:15:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/we-the-poems/</guid>
      <description>Every so often some jackass from a conservative outlet will point to government expenditure on poets as a sign that spending is out of control. Two years ago, for example, KIRO ran a story headlined “City will pay poet $10K to hold performances, workshops” that seemed to be designed to whip commenters into an uproar. In terms of state and city budgets, the numbers we’re talking about aren’t even big enough to count as pocket change: the Washington state Poet Laureate position receives a $20,000 annual stipend from the state (though mostly that money comes from grants and not taxes) and Seattle’s Civic Poet earns that aforementioned $10,000 for a two-year stint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>These comics grab back</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/these-comics-grab-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 12:20:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/these-comics-grab-back/</guid>
      <description>The Seattle-area cartoonist behind Grab Back Comics, an industrious woman using the pseudonym “Erma Blood,” says that her site was born in those early, helpless days just after the 2016 presidential election. Blood took her wife on a vacation to celebrate their first wedding anniversary “and it was very sweet,” she says. “But my experience of the coverage of sexual assaults and harassment during the election had really taken a toll.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enemies of the state</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/enemies-of-the-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 10:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/enemies-of-the-state/</guid>
      <description>As a news consumer in the 21st century, I try to measure every piece of political news that flows down my social media streams against two different questions:
 Does this piece paint the politicians in question as mercilessly, cartoonishly evil? As much as I detest Donald Trump, I do not believe that he does things because he wants to be evil. Nobody is the villain in their own stories, and an unrealistic portrait of Trump (and Ryan and McConnell and so on) can contribute to that dreaded “liberal bubble” that pundits warn us all about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It was always this way, until it wasn&#39;t</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/it-was-always-this-way-until-it-wasnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 12:07:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/it-was-always-this-way-until-it-wasnt/</guid>
      <description>I’m in southern California.
I’m in southern California because Seattle’s cloudy and rainy weather has finally become too much for me. The year 2017 has brought with it a few pristine sunny days, but those days have been the briefest of punctuation marks in a long, run-on sentence of gray skies and brutally cold rain. This winter has tested my patience, and I have a few days off work and so I’m visiting some friends and following the sun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Something fishy</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/something-fishy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 12:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/something-fishy/</guid>
      <description>Mark Kurlansky’s non-fiction book about cod, titled Cod, is a critically praised bestseller that’s bordering on modern-classic status. It’s easy to forget that when Cod was released in 1997, nobody expected a book about a goddamned fish, of all things, to change the course of publishing. But Cod kicked off a craze of popular books devoted to the history of everyday objects — Kurlansky’s own Salt followed soon after Cod, and other books about screwdrivers and paper and rats tumbled down the pipeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strange bedfellows</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/strange-bedfellows/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/strange-bedfellows/</guid>
      <description>Ever since Socrates asked that Homer be censored and the poets be exiled from his beloved republic, philosophy and poetry have been on less than civil terms. Hegel, for example, thought that poetry was no longer up to the task of representing the Absolute, and therefore must give way to philosophy. On the side of the poets, Keats, in his lengthy poem “Lamia,” condemns “cold philosophy” for her removal of beauty from the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myself, my self</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/myself-my-self/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 12:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/myself-my-self/</guid>
      <description>No writer in Seattle is more interested in the raw physicality of words than Doug Nufer. Nufer is interested in the shape of words, the multiple meanings they carry, the sound of them when spoken aloud, the look of them when aligned on the page next to each other. The meat and bones of words — before even the meaning imbues them with a kind of soul — fascinates him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stitch by stitch by broken stitch</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/stitch-by-stitch-by-broken-stitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 12:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/stitch-by-stitch-by-broken-stitch/</guid>
      <description>Okay, look: you’ve probably had a bad couple of years and I don’t want to judge your emotional pain. But unless you’re one of the dozen or so music legends who died in 2016, the odds are good that Sherman Alexie has been having a worse time than you.
Alexie’s mother Lillian, with whom he had a very complicated relationship, passed away in the summer of 2015. In the aftermath of Lillian’s funeral, something in Alexie’s heart cracked open and a flood of poems poured out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let Lightning Snake reveal yourself to you</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/let-lightning-snake-reveal-yourself-to-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/let-lightning-snake-reveal-yourself-to-you/</guid>
      <description>Around the time I first read Lightning Snake, I was gifted an old vinyl of The Moody Blues’ In Search of the Lost Chord by a regular member at the sensory deprivation tank spa where I sometimes work. On the inside of this record there’s an artist’s note. It says: A YANTRA is used in much the same way as a mantra, although visually. The YANTRA is something that can hold the mind to a form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazing grace</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/amazing-grace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 11:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/amazing-grace/</guid>
      <description>In the New Testament, Paul is single-minded about grace. He writes about grace relentlessly, until the word becomes a catchall for pretty much anything that is good and true in the world. Grace is God’s love. Grace is the power through which you are cleansed of sin. Grace is what gives you the will to get through another day, even though every cell in your body is telling you to stay in bed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Bones</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/good-bones/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 12:20:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/good-bones/</guid>
      <description>I’ve written before about the blow suffered by Seattle’s literary community when poet Joan Swift died in March. At 90 years old, Swift represented a clear link to Seattle’s literary past (she was one of Seattle poetry godfather Theodore Roethke’s last students), and given her propensity to guide and encourage younger poets, her influence will be felt for many decades to come.
I talked with Swift’s friends about her life and legacy, and everyone had a favorite Swift poem, a work that would burrow deep into their chests and change them forever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing in between the lines</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/writing-in-between-the-lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 12:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/writing-in-between-the-lines/</guid>
      <description>Nobody makes writing sound more romantic, important, and magical than a writer, and that’s why writing about writers is a writer’s favorite pastime. Visit any bookstore’s how-to-write section and you’ll find volume after volume that describes writing as an art and a craft and a calling and a sacred trust. A writer can make writing sound like the most important calling in the world, and the only thing writers love to do more than publicly praise the work of another writer is to talk shit about other writers in the bar after the reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It should exist, but it doesn&#39;t</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/it-should-exist-but-it-doesnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 09:46:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/it-should-exist-but-it-doesnt/</guid>
      <description>This book doesn’t exist, but it should. Imagine it: it’s a giant, full-color, hardcover affair — sturdy and substantial. The kind of book that forces a little grunt out of you when you pull it off the shelf. The kind of book that thuds onto a kitchen counter like an announcement, like a statement of purpose.
It’s a cookbook. But it’s not like any cookbook that you’ve ever seen before. Once you flip it open, you’ll see why: it’s a comic book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reviewing is a strong word for what happens here</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/reviewing-is-a-strong-word-for-what-happens-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/reviewing-is-a-strong-word-for-what-happens-here/</guid>
      <description>/* Webfont: Lato-Italic */@font-face { font-family: &#39;LatoWeb&#39;; src: url(&#39;http://helpers.seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/dederer/Lato-Italic.eot&#39;); /* IE9 Compat Modes */ src: url(&#39;http://helpers.seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/dederer/Lato-Italic.eot?#iefix&#39;) format(&#39;embedded-opentype&#39;), /* IE6-IE8 */ url(&#39;http://helpers.seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/dederer/Lato-Italic.woff2&#39;) format(&#39;woff2&#39;), /* Modern Browsers */ url(&#39;http://helpers.seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/dederer/Lato-Italic.woff&#39;) format(&#39;woff&#39;), /* Modern Browsers */ url(&#39;http://helpers.seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/dederer/Lato-Italic.ttf&#39;) format(&#39;truetype&#39;); font-style: italic; font-weight: normal; text-rendering: optimizeLegibility; } /* Webfont: Lato-Regular */@font-face { font-family: &#39;LatoWeb&#39;; src: url(&#39;http://helpers.seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/dederer/Lato-Regular.eot&#39;); /* IE9 Compat Modes */ src: url(&#39;http://helpers.seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/dederer/Lato-Regular.eot?#iefix&#39;) format(&#39;embedded-opentype&#39;), /* IE6-IE8 */ url(&#39;http://helpers.seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/dederer/Lato-Regular.woff2&#39;) format(&#39;woff2&#39;), /* Modern Browsers */ url(&#39;http://helpers.seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/dederer/Lato-Regular.woff&#39;) format(&#39;woff&#39;), /* Modern Browsers */ url(&#39;http://helpers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stand up poetry</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/stand-up-poetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 12:27:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/stand-up-poetry/</guid>
      <description>Funny poems are tough to pull off. I’m not talking, here, about poems with humor in them; almost every good poem has at least one funny thing smuggled inside of it. No, I mean poems with punchlines, poems written with the intent of making readers laugh out loud. Those are very hard to get right; too often, funny poems veer into dad joke territory. They try too hard, they screech too loud, and they flop gracelessly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;ll laugh, you&#39;ll cry</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/youll-laugh-youll-cry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/youll-laugh-youll-cry/</guid>
      <description>Patricia Lockwood is one of the best poets working in America today. Plenty of critics try to diminish that standing by dinging Lockwood for successfully using the internet like an adult human in the year 2017. In the first sentence of her review of Lockwood’s new book, Priestdaddy, Financial Times critic Suzi Feay praises Lockwood backhandedly for “her zany mastery of Twitter.” James Parker in his Atlantic review of Priestdaddy sniffs that “Like Donald Trump, [Lockwood] does pretty well on Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seattle, step by step</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/seattle-step-by-step/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 12:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/seattle-step-by-step/</guid>
      <description>It’s easy for newcomers to be deterred by the hills or the rain, but the truth is that Seattle is one of the most walkable cities in the country. Unlike, say, the ugly monotony of Florida cities or the imposing boulevards of California cities, Seattle feels pedestrian-sized. There’s enough happening on street level to reward a wanderer’s attention, and there are enough straight-shot trails available between neighborhoods to make long-distance travel relatively easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where, and when, history happens</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/where-and-when-history-happens/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/where-and-when-history-happens/</guid>
      <description>When I was growing up I believed that history happened elsewhere – Plymouth Rock, the Alamo, the Oregon Trail. I never thought of National City, where I lived, as having a history. Even though we learned in fourth grade that the first Californians were Indians, the implication we received was that they had vanished with the progress of “civilization.”
Several years ago, my sister sent me a book called Early National City issued by Arcadia Publishing, the “leading local history publisher in the United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A colorful chorus of voices</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-colorful-chorus-of-voices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 11:40:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-colorful-chorus-of-voices/</guid>
      <description>![](/webhook-uploads/1491539563891/IMG_4245.JPG)
Individually, these pamphlets are not much to look at— a page or two of color paper, printed neatly, folded in a tight crease down the middle, and stapled. Bundled together in stacks of five, though, they’re quite substantial. On the back of every individual pamphlet is the name of the publisher (Mount Analogue,) the publication credit (“Risograph printing by Paper Press Punch,”) a website (www.mount-analogue.com,) and the date of publication, as well as this disclaimer:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trouble in paradise</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/trouble-in-paradise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 11:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/trouble-in-paradise/</guid>
      <description>Mount Analogue publisher Colleen Louise Barry first encountered Halie Theoharides’s blog Final Rose as a fan. In her interview with me, Barry’s enthusiasm for the project was clear. Final Rose, she explained, was made up of “all of these screenshots [Theoharides] would take while she was watching The Bachelor and The Bachelorette with closed captioning on. She would take a screenshot whenever the text and the image on the screen were doing something interesting or disturbing or funny.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The backwards map</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-backwards-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 11:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-backwards-map/</guid>
      <description>You might find it hard to keep your footing if you charge at the poems in Ted Powers’s new collection Manners in the conventional way. Breaking into the first line and barreling straight down to the bottom doesn’t work. If you read these poems from beginning to end, it’s easy to get lost and turned around, until you start chasing after yourself in a recursive loop.
I find it’s easier to flip through Manners, to cast your eyes about and wait for them to hook onto something muscular and twitchy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding his voice</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/finding-his-voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 12:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/finding-his-voice/</guid>
      <description>Bellingham poet Robert Lashley is probably best known for his stage presence. Lashley comes from the spoken word scene, and he is one of the best readers in the region: there’s a moment in every one of his performances when he shifts from mild-mannered stage patter to the poet with that voice, and it’s always a bracing moment.
You can always tell when someone in the audience has never attended a Lashley reading before because they rear up when that voice makes itself known.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One of a kind</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/one-of-a-kind/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 11:23:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/one-of-a-kind/</guid>
      <description>We think of books not as commodities but as symbols of individuality. But centuries before the Industrial Revolution, printing presses were mass-producing books. In fact, books are the first item that we mass-produced as a species, and we’ve gotten really good at making sure that every copy of a specific book is exactly the same as every other copy.
Part of the reason Jeff Bezos chose books as the commodity on which to establish his online retailing venture was the fact that books, as products, are so uniform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dreaming beyond fiction and nonfiction</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/dreaming-beyond-fiction-and-nonfiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 12:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/dreaming-beyond-fiction-and-nonfiction/</guid>
      <description>Bruja is the Spanish word for witch, and it’s possible that the witch in Wendy C. Ortiz’s latest book is Wendy herself. Not only does Ortiz watch a cheetah chasing a possum through a window, she manages to catch a bear whispering into the ear of another bear, and she is present while a sea turtle turns into a seal. She survives several shark attacks, jumps into a car that flies over rooftops, has an affair with Governor Arnold Schwarzenegger, and attempts to murder her mother.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No one owns a city</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/no-one-owns-a-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 10:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/no-one-owns-a-city/</guid>
      <description>When you watch a movie, you’re handing over a remarkable amount of control over to the artists who made the film: the movie starts, the narrative unspools at its own pace, and then it’s over. You can’t really get through a movie’s story any quicker than its director intended without fast-forwarding or skipping or taking some other drastic action that breaks the art.
Conversely, when you read a book the author has virtually no control over the time that the story takes in your mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The fire is in the book</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-fire-is-in-the-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-fire-is-in-the-book/</guid>
      <description>She hurt a man’s ego and there was a war and terrible carnage.
This is Sayantani Dasgupta&amp;rsquo;s nutshell recap of the Hindu story of Draupadi, a girl made of fire, in her book of essays Fire Girl: Essays of India, America, and the In-Between. Draupadi, considered a feminist icon, didn&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to speak her mind, so the miffed male unleashed the forces at his disposal and pretty much wrecked the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A portrait, in black and white</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-portrait-in-black-and-white/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 12:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-portrait-in-black-and-white/</guid>
      <description>Cartoonists don’t often get a chance at second acts. We expect comics artists to keep drawing the same immortal characters over and over until they grow old and die, like Charles Schulz; or until they retire from the business, like Gary Larson; or until they perfect their art and ascend to the literary heavens, like Lynda Barry.
Tacoma cartoonist Peter Bagge, then, is the great exception. His semi-autobiographical Buddy Bradley comics — partially canonized last year in the deluxe two-volume reprint collection The Complete Neat Stuff — is largely considered one of the cornerstones of 1990s alternative comics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heavy is the head</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/heavy-is-the-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 11:49:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/heavy-is-the-head/</guid>
      <description>You see you wouldn’t ask why the rose that grew from the concrete had damaged petals. On the contrary, we would all celebrate its tenacity. We would all love its will to reach for the sun. Well, we are the roses. This is the concrete. These are my damaged petals. Don’t ask me why. Ask me how. –Tupac Shakur, “The Rose That Grew From Concrete” in the hood / everyone is driven to kill / by some kind of distinct / famine –Hanif Willis-Abdurraqib, “On Hunger” Hunger and famine — more precisely, the ever-present avoidance of them — are the ordering principles of Hanif Willis-Abdurraqib’s first collection of poetry, *The Crown Ain’t Worth Much*.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>With a single step</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/with-a-single-step/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 12:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/with-a-single-step/</guid>
      <description>Eventually we’ll get to the stars, but first we have to walk.
 I do not like to run. I’ll sprint for a bus now and again, but the rhythm of jogging, the enthusiastic bouncing, has always felt artificial to me.
Instead, I prefer to walk. Not jaunts to the corner store or after-dinner strolls through the neighborhood. I can walk a marathon every Saturday — in fact, I basically require it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The stars my destination</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-stars-my-destination/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 12:38:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-stars-my-destination/</guid>
      <description>It seems that nearly every page of Seattle author Kevin Emerson’s young adult science fiction novel Last Day on Mars has a blinking light on it. Since the book takes place on a Mars colony in the far-flung year of 2213, most of the lights are on console panels or spacefaring equipment. There are some signal lights, too, and a few twinkling stars. But the book is really about one giant blinking light: the sun, billions of years ahead of schedule, is about to go supernova and then collapse, rendering our solar system inhospitable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wait your turn</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/wait-your-turn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 09:50:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/wait-your-turn/</guid>
      <description>It’s not often that I find an epiphany in a book. Sure, books deepen my understanding and broaden my perspective, but an out-and-out epiphany? A miraculous moment in which the fog clears and my vision focuses on something new? That’s a rare thing. Arlie Russell Hochschild’s Strangers in Their Own Land delivered such a new insight to me, and it’s on a topic I’ve been batting around in my head for months — maybe years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Seattle globalist</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-seattle-globalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 12:09:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-seattle-globalist/</guid>
      <description>There comes a time in every poet’s life when they must set aside their lofty goals and get on down to the pressing business of fucking. I’m not talking about flowery love poems — I mean the kind of horny writing that drops all metaphor and imagery and makes it clear that genital-to-genital contact is about to happen.
The poems in the beginning of Maged Zaher’s new collection, Opting Out: Early, New &amp;amp; Collected Poems 2000 – 2015, are about as thirsty as poems can get.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All happy families are alike</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/all-happy-families-are-alike/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 13:01:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/all-happy-families-are-alike/</guid>
      <description>Novels are terrific engines of social change. No form of art is as effective at putting you inside the minds of other people; to read a novel, you must be willing and welcoming to someone else’s perspectives. Being a receptive reader is a state of grace that you never experience in, say, politics. It’s a place of possibility, an opportunity to create change in yourself. Harriet Beecher Stowe understood this, and Charles Dickens, and Harper Lee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding each other in the dark</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/finding-each-other-in-the-dark/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/finding-each-other-in-the-dark/</guid>
      <description>It’s easy to see why Rebecca Solnit’s book Hope in the Dark has become an independent bookstore bestseller in the months since Donald Trump won the election. After all, it’s a book written by one of our smartest cultural critics about finding hope in difficult political times. Readers know they can trust Solnit to not be too Pollyannaish in her conclusions about hope. She’s physically incapable of offering a bromide, or a cliché, or an unsupported premise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Angry Doodler reviews Private Citizens by Tony Tulathimutte</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-angry-doodler-reviews-private-citizens-by-tony-tulathimutte/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 11:56:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-angry-doodler-reviews-private-citizens-by-tony-tulathimutte/</guid>
      <description>![](/webhook-uploads/1485567516778/PrivateCitizensFlat.jpg)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quid pro quo</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/quid-pro-quo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 13:04:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/quid-pro-quo/</guid>
      <description>We’ve been trained by popular culture to visualize serial killers in a very specific way: they’re sleek, efficient, charming hunters of humans. Sociopathic and hyper-intelligent, serial killers are always five steps ahead of everyone else. They’re willful, clever, highly manipulative loners, and they’re relentlessly driven by some lone traumatic incident in their childhood. They’re not so much human beings as puzzle-boxes to entertain and alarm us for a couple hours until they’re finally captured and the closing credits roll.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Throw Yourself at the Ground and Miss</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/how-to-throw-yourself-at-the-ground-and-miss/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 13:15:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/how-to-throw-yourself-at-the-ground-and-miss/</guid>
      <description>When a young man named Gary Groth established a magazine to address comics as a serious literary art form, he encountered one small problem: at the time — in the mid-1970s — there were no comics worthy of his criticism. So Groth decided to publish the books that he wanted to write about in his magazine. That was the beginning of Fantagraphics Books, the self-described “publisher of the world’s greatest cartoonists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A room full of citizens</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-room-full-of-citizens/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 09:54:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-room-full-of-citizens/</guid>
      <description>This is unprofessional for a critic, but I have to gush: I loved reading Claudia Rankine’s book Citizen: An American Lyric. I love everything about this book: I love the look of it, the feel of it, the words and the design and the passion and the craft of it. Citizen, to me, feels like the future of non-fiction books: a beautiful, book-length essay delivered in raw, vital chunks of text, interspersed with color photos and relevant pieces of art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choose your own year in reading</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/choose-your-own-year-in-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 10:02:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/choose-your-own-year-in-reading/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes I get a little obsessive about my reading. As a child, I recall spending one New Year’s Eve reading Terry Pratchett’s novel Sourcery as quickly as I could — partly because it captured my attention so intently, and partly because I wanted to close the year by finishing a book. Further, I wanted to begin the year with a brand-new book. This desire to start the new year with a new book felt like a powerful urge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tourists in the time stream</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/tourists-in-the-time-stream/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 11:56:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/tourists-in-the-time-stream/</guid>
      <description>“I’m bored of the early 21st,” our narrator Spens tells us at the beginning of Robert Dickson’s sci-fi thriller The Tourist. By “21st,” he means “century.” He’s a tour guide leading groups of time-traveling tourists on journeys through our mundane present — the travelers are horrified and fascinated by our shopping malls, for instance. Mostly, he sits and drinks coffee and eats pastry for the novelty of it (it&amp;rsquo;s simultaneously tasteless and too sweet for his future-palate) while his group wanders around having innocuous interactions with 21st century residents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blinded by the supernova</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/blinded-by-the-supernova/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 11:55:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/blinded-by-the-supernova/</guid>
      <description>Thomas Friedman has always felt most comfortable analyzing topics from unusually high vantage points. From this perch — his critics would say ivory tower — he is a master at scanning the current terrain of our world, diagnosing where humanity is heading, and offering a roadmap to success.
In Thank You for Being Late, Friedman returns to this tried-and-true formula, focusing his gaze on why our politics and society feel so off-kilter today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are God’s crash test dummy</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/you-are-gods-crash-test-dummy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 12:32:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/you-are-gods-crash-test-dummy/</guid>
      <description>One of the things that I hate most about Donald Trump is that he’s completely and irrevocably changed the way that I read. Like 9&amp;frasl;11 or the election of Barack Obama, Donald Trump’s presidency has altered the tenor and tone of entire books for me. I’ll never again be able to read a presidential biography, for example, without the specter of Trump lingering just beyond the last few pages of the book, like the punchline to a bad fart joke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A journey into the head of a stalker</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-journey-into-the-head-of-a-stalker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 11:46:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-journey-into-the-head-of-a-stalker/</guid>
      <description>There are fewer greater pleasures in literature than watching a serious writer of fiction wade into the denigrated waters of genre and emerge with something exquisitely written yet propulsively entertaining all at the same time. Yes, Graham Greene produced enduring novels about British colonialism, but were any of them better than Brighton Rock, a tale of a gang war in a resort town in southern England just before World War II?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bernie Sanders is the last Democrat standing</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/bernie-sanders-is-the-last-democrat-standing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 09:50:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/bernie-sanders-is-the-last-democrat-standing/</guid>
      <description>![](/webhook-uploads/1480578563294/BernieSanders.jpg)
Never in the history of Seattle readings has an author so brazenly stepped on his own introduction. Last night at University Temple United Methodist Church, University Book Store CEO Louise Little was seemingly just getting started with her introduction for Senator Bernie Sanders when a raucous wall of applause broke out in the back of the church and proceeded to the front of the building. It was so loud, and so continuous, that Little’s voice was entirely drowned out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regarding Lucia Perillo</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/regarding-lucia-perillo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 12:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/regarding-lucia-perillo/</guid>
      <description>In 1987 I bought a small, struggling bookstore in my neighborhood. I was a godsend for the then-owner and the store was a godsend for me. Prior, I had studied to become, and became, a rehabilitation counselor. That means, seen in hindsight, that I had engaged in expensive self-help at a very good university and then wandered into a career. The bookstore was a much better fit as it allowed me to associate with books and their makers — loves from a very early age — rather than keeping company with other damaged people and their insurance companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American elegy</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/american-elegy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/american-elegy/</guid>
      <description>_Hillbilly Elegy_ is the first book in our new reading club [Reading Through It](http://www.seattlereviewofbooks.com/notes/2016/11/15/reading-through-it-join-us-for-a-discussion-of-how-to-move-forward-in-donald-trumps-america/ &#34;The Seattle Review of Books - Reading Through It: Join us for a discussion of how to move forward in Donald Trump’s America&#34;), where we come together in partnership with _The Seattle Weekly_, and Third Place Books in Seward Park, to discuss how to move forward in Trump&#39;s America. Join us, Wednesday December 7th, and 7pm. All are welcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work work work work work</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/work-work-work-work-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 12:54:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/work-work-work-work-work/</guid>
      <description>The nature of work has changed significantly in the last 50 years, and it’s frankly kind of amazing that there’s not rioting in the streets over it. Think about it: at one point in American history, employers were expected to offer full-time jobs with benefits and a retirement program. Fewer and fewer Americans ever enjoy that kind of a relationship, and the rush into piecework only gains speed with the passage of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The fascist within</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-fascist-within/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 12:05:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-fascist-within/</guid>
      <description>I shouldn’t have been surprised by Brexit. And I shouldn’t have been surprised by the intensity of Donald Trump’s support among a volatile electorate. Living in a too-homogenous left-wing enclave on the West Coast, I was caught off guard. But I should have known better: I study racial and religious politics in Europe for a living, and this story is so familiar it hurts. So when the New York Times posted a video of Trump supporters screaming vicious racist epithets at a rally a few weeks ago, to tell us all to look!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help selfie</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/help-selfie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/help-selfie/</guid>
      <description>I have the usual prejudices about self-help books. They hook you with flattery, pamper your ego, promise easy fixes, make you a sucker and then a recidivist. They’re banal, corny, embarrassing, predatory, and mercenary to the tune of a growing multi-billion dollar industry. They’re cheap cons: they love you and leave you desperate for more. Self-help isn’t real help. On the other hand, being a wet blanket 24&amp;frasl;7 is unyielding hard work, especially when a person needs a pick-me-up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I like to be in America</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/i-like-to-be-in-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 13:01:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/i-like-to-be-in-america/</guid>
      <description>Fairly or unfairly, short stories set in the domestic sphere of the American 20th Century tend to live in the shade of the two famous white Johns — Updike and Cheever. Those two men have become synonymous with midcentury ennui of the upper middle class, a style which has been parodied and mocked and prized apart with postmodern angst and fastidiously replicated by sincere young writers, even to this day, in mainstream literary journals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The smartest person in the voting booth</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-smartest-person-in-the-voting-booth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 12:01:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-smartest-person-in-the-voting-booth/</guid>
      <description>Democracy’s recent ubiquity is remarkably novel in human history. Yet even in its infancy we are unhesitatingly willing to crown it as the universal ideal of good and just government. To the critical mind, democracy’s virtues can appear overindulged.
After all, unless you came to this democratic nation under your own power, we have not actually chosen to live under this form of rule. Rather, we have awakened to the situation and tacitly consented to our present state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>He who should not be named</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/he-who-should-not-be-named/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 12:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/he-who-should-not-be-named/</guid>
      <description>I am so sick and tired of Donald Trump. I know this is not a unique opinion, or an especially interesting one, but it is an opinion that I want to shout in a very public place, or paint on a giant wall somewhere, with “sick” and “tired” both underlined three times for emphasis. It’s an imperative, a biological urge, like being hungry or needing to use a bathroom. My body is rejecting Donald Trump the way it would cast out a foreign organ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selling mansions in heaven</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/selling-mansions-in-heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 09:59:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/selling-mansions-in-heaven/</guid>
      <description>As a lifelong atheist and comics fan — maybe not necessarily in that order — I was especially primed as a young man to fall in a kind of kitschy love with Jack Chick’s comics. In the late 1990s, I embraced Chick’s comics on the same level of so-bad-it’s-good appreciation that others would bring to a cheesy horror movie, say, or an embarrassingly mediocre record purchased from the discount bin at a thrift shop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After the end of the world</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/after-the-end-of-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 12:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/after-the-end-of-the-world/</guid>
      <description>In high school, Michelle Tea’s memoir/novels Valencia and The Chelsea Whistle flooded my virgin imagination with hope and lust for the adventures I had to look forward to as an adult queer. I particularly remember her description of one relatively understated float in her parade of lovers and/or lovers of a woman she was seeing (that it’s hard to remember which should evoke the grandeur of the parade.) She wrote that she saw the sleeping woman’s mousy brown head poking out from under a blanket, and couldn’t recall when the sight had become a common occurrence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There&#39;s No Place Like Home</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/theres-no-place-like-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 13:06:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/theres-no-place-like-home/</guid>
      <description>I do not believe it is hyperbolic to say that a little piece of Seattle died on the day that the Seattle Post-Intelligencer stopped publishing a daily print edition. The Seattle Times publishes some wonderful journalism, but a single newspaper cannot accurately portray the entire soul of a city. In the years since the P-I print edition died, though, we have seen some significant online publications grow to fill that void.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;I&#39;m from Bellevue&#34;</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/im-from-bellevue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/im-from-bellevue/</guid>
      <description>One summer day, early in the 21st-century, I’m southbound on Bellevue’s NE 104th, approaching the NE 8th intersection, for generations the city’s main one. It takes me two traffic lights to get through, and as I wait I study the towers just to my left (“Bellevue Place”) and a range of other buildings ahead and to my right. Steel gleams in the diffused light through the usual cloud cover. I’ve ridden through here all my life, and driven it for over three decades, but I recognize nothing, only the slight downward slope as I pass through Kemperville down to Main Street.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Count how many notifications you get while reading this review</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/count-how-many-notifications-you-get-while-reading-this-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/count-how-many-notifications-you-get-while-reading-this-review/</guid>
      <description>David M. Levy’s Mindful Tech: How to Bring Balance to Our Digital Lives begins with a description of a viral YouTube clip, which is fitting for a book about digital distractions. In the video, a woman strides through a shopping mall, eyes fixed on her smartphone, oblivious to her surroundings until she tumbles headfirst into a fountain. Just as quickly she climbs out and charges forward on her way.
The anecdote could come off as smug, a finger-wagging lesson for mocking the woman or scolding us all for fixating on our mobile screens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>...and I feel fine</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/and-i-feel-fine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 10:03:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/and-i-feel-fine/</guid>
      <description>Maybe this election cycle, with its casual invocation of nuclear war and portraits of American landscapes as dystopian nightmares, will finally break the fever of apocalyptic fiction that has held a tight grip on America’s popular consciousness for well over a decade now. Maybe — and this is one of those predictions that will likely sound very dumb six months from now — maybe it’s time to think about a better future again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The poet says what the politician cannot</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-poet-says-what-the-politician-cannot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 13:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-poet-says-what-the-politician-cannot/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve attended a meeting of the Seattle City Council over the last few months — as part of the #BlocktheBunker movement, say, or as a worker fighting for secure scheduling — odds are good you’ve heard at least one poet read their work aloud. As part of her role as Seattle’s very first Civic Poet, Claudia Castro Luna curates the poetry readings that open City Council meetings. To many who attend council meetings on official business, this is probably just a bit of pointless civic nonsense to tolerate, some grandstanding to keep the arts community placated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traveled the world and the seven seas</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/traveled-the-world-and-the-seven-seas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 11:48:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/traveled-the-world-and-the-seven-seas/</guid>
      <description>The J. Peterman catalog is a seminal 1990s artifact. The catalogs, which featured expensive vintage-style clothing from far-flung locales rendered in hand-drawn illustrations, were best known for their overwritten catalog copy. The text had an upscale, worldly air, and it almost always skittered on the line of self-parody, relaying adventures in foreign lands with language that was at once self-important and wildly entertaining, overblown and amusing.
Here’s a sample of a J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The embedded cartoonist</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-embedded-cartoonist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 12:36:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-embedded-cartoonist/</guid>
      <description>1. Journalism is the pursuit of truth. 
In 2010, cartoonist Sarah Glidden accompanied two reporters from the Seattle Globalist as they traveled through Iraq and Syria on a two-month trip. The Globalist reporters were there to find and report on as many stories as possible. Glidden was there, more or less, to report on the Globalist reporters. Six years later, Glidden’s full account of the trip has finally been published as a book titled Rolling Blackouts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharing the last of our food</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/sharing-the-last-of-our-food/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/sharing-the-last-of-our-food/</guid>
      <description>The first time I encountered the ravaging effects of post-traumatic stress disorder or PTSD was when my husband went into surgery for a rare cancer and came out without any memory of our life. He died on the table that night, but his body remained. He had an anoxic insult, a brain injury, and he lost much of the ability to remember what happened yesterday or ten minutes ago. And surprisingly, he lost something most didn’t at first recognize was possible to lose in a cancer treatment &amp;mdash; the long-term memories of his life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You always hurt the ones you love</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/you-always-hurt-the-ones-you-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 13:03:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/you-always-hurt-the-ones-you-love/</guid>
      <description>Maria Semple’s second novel, Where’d You Go Bernadette, was an international bestseller, the kind of publishing phenomenon that would be difficult for anyone to replicate. (I’ve seen it on bestseller walls in bookstores all over the country and in airports all over the world.) Something about Semple’s novel appealed to a huge swath of the reading population. Perhaps it had something to do with the title character’s hilarious distaste for Seattle, which was at that time just becoming recognized as the most up-and-coming city in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Out of the running</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/out-of-the-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 12:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/out-of-the-running/</guid>
      <description>Every presidential cycle has its losers — the zany dimbulbs like Herman Cain, the gallant nerds like Dennis Kucinich, the unloveable schmucks like Rick Santorum. You can’t help but wonder when you watch these losers speak why, exactly, they’re bothering to run for office in the first place. Don’t they realize they can’t win? Do they believe they’re running for a greater cause?
Or maybe they’re just that delusional — perhaps when they wake up and drag combs across their heads in a bathroom mirror in a Day’s Inn outside of Des Moines, they see someone destined for the seat of power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feminism a la carte</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/feminism-a-la-carte/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/feminism-a-la-carte/</guid>
      <description>It feels like these are end times that we are living in. Black men are being murdered by police with impunity. Nationalist movements reminiscent of pre-WWII era fascism are cropping up all over the world. And we have somehow all become willing participants in a surveillance state, happily carrying around devices that track our every movement, and enable us to share intimate details for the state and corporations to monitor and mine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counterfactual, counterhistory, counter memory</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/counterfactual-counterhistory-counter-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/counterfactual-counterhistory-counter-memory/</guid>
      <description>Counterfactual history, or counterhistory, has its signature moves: Killing Hitler. Letting the other side win the war. Imagining a home for the Jewish people outside of Israel.
A prominent example of a Jewish-themed counterhistory is Michael Chabon’s The Yiddish Policemen’s Union, in which the U.S. government, instead of supporting the formation of the modern state of Israel, grants a temporary lease to the Jewish people for Alaskan territory. The novel follows a down-on-his-luck detective trying to solve a case at the cusp of the reversion of Alaska to the United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everfair, in love and war</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/everfair-in-love-and-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 13:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/everfair-in-love-and-war/</guid>
      <description>You’re either the kind of reader who digs books that have maps and family trees in the first few pages, or you’re not. Some readers — and for the sake of full disclosure, this is where my loyalties lie — tend to barrel through books all sharklike, never turning back or stopping. Others prefer to take their time; these are the people who love the luxury of flipping back and forth, consulting the character lists in the front of the book and thumbing over to the glossary in the back as needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American odyssey</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/american-odyssey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 11:59:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/american-odyssey/</guid>
      <description>Colson Whitehead never writes the same book twice. This is possibly why, despite the fact that he’s been the most consistently excellent novelist to be published by a mainstream New York house over the last two decades, he hasn’t been able to build the audience that he deserves. In these times of fractured fandoms and increasingly algorithm-centric recommendations, people who enjoy Whitehead’s personal, semiautobiographical novel might not even bother to try his zombie novel, and fans of his zombie novel might not think his gigantic examination of the American myth of John Henry is for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Far from the tree</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/far-from-the-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 12:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/far-from-the-tree/</guid>
      <description>Getting paid to travel, eat, and write seems like nothing short of the perfect job. Matt Gross, a foodie and born adventurer, held this job for years, immersing himself repeatedly in cultures all over the globe. Having written the Frugal Traveler column in the New York Times for several years, he has perfected the art of conveying a sense of place. The premise of his column was simple: travel somewhere, stick to a budget, and give readers tips on how to best experience the destination while living frugally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A message from the future</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-message-from-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 10:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-message-from-the-future/</guid>
      <description>You’ve seen this future before. Lucas Varela’s new comic The Longest Day of the Future is stuffed full of familiar sci-fi tropes: future humans walk around their future cities wearing sexless jumpsuits, unless they’re mad scientists in white lab coats and goggles. Aliens have giant skulls and fly around in saucers. Robots are comical figures with telescoping arms. Fleshy pink tentacles leap out at you when you least expect them. Portals enable instantaneous travel anywhere on Earth, and even into other dimensions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strange huge illuminations</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/strange-huge-illuminations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 11:55:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/strange-huge-illuminations/</guid>
      <description>In a Paris Review interview, Cynthia Ozick, then fifty-two, confesses to her incredulous interviewer, Tom Teicholz, that she has no audience:
 &amp;hellip;I want to be read. I know I can’t be “popular,” and I regard this as a major failing&amp;hellip;but&amp;hellip;.[v]ery few people read me&amp;hellip;  Some might interpret this as writerly anxiety or false modesty because the work of few contemporary authors has as serious a readership among the literati.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancer in the cells</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/cancer-in-the-cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/cancer-in-the-cells/</guid>
      <description>One day in the not-so-distant future, Americans will look back on the way we currently treat our prisoners with shame and regret. Over-incarceration abounds — particularly of African-American and Hispanic men — and rehabilitation is barely an afterthought. Drug crimes are still hugely over-represented (as of 2014, half of all prisoners sentenced to more than a year in prison were there due to the War on Drugs) and the race and class issues in our prison system are so glaringly obvious that to call them “subtext” would be insulting to the very concept of text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private eyes are watching you</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/private-eyes-are-watching-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 11:36:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/private-eyes-are-watching-you/</guid>
      <description>In the beginning of Suite Vénitienne, Sophie Calle writes that for some unknown reason, she started choosing strangers at random on the street and following them without their knowledge. She’d take photos of them and write little notations tracking their movements. Then, her little game escalated:
At the end of January 1980, on the streets of Paris, I followed a man whom I lost sight of a few minutes later in the crowd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women are from Mars</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/women-are-from-mars/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 11:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/women-are-from-mars/</guid>
      <description>A rule of thumb for writing science fiction is to start with the world outside our window, change one thing, and then see how that affects the world. Often the thing that’s changed is a technological breakthrough — faster-than-light travel, or nanomachines — and sometimes it’s a societal shift, like talking animals. In Portland author David D. Levine’s Arabella of Mars, the one new thing is a physical law: there is no vacuum of space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The boy wonder grows up</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-boy-wonder-grows-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-boy-wonder-grows-up/</guid>
      <description>For decades, Peter Bagge has reigned as Seattle’s mightiest cartoonist. He’s a high-functioning artist, which is to say that his work is strong in just about any way an artist’s work can be measured: he’s prolific, he’s stylistically fascinating, his comics are easy to read and well-written, he has a unique viewpoint, and his work has deepened over time. Though he’s been publishing work for over three decades now, Bagge’s best work — a biography of Margaret Sanger titled Woman Rebel — was published in late 2013, and there’s no sign that he’s slowing down in terms of output and quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dredding every minute of it</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/dredding-every-minute-of-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/dredding-every-minute-of-it/</guid>
      <description>&#34;A good hero is hard to beat, and a good villain is hard to beat, so why not combine them?&#34; - John Wagner
 ![](/webhook-uploads/1470638973194/01.jpg)
 In a galaxy far, far away&amp;hellip; When I was growing up in rural Bedfordshire in the Eighties, there were fairly limited options for sci-fi action fans to get their fix. On TV, there were three &amp;mdash; then four &amp;mdash; channels that might show the odd Star Trek or Doctor Who episode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things come together, things fall apart again</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/things-come-together-things-fall-apart-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 11:59:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/things-come-together-things-fall-apart-again/</guid>
      <description>The first time I read Things Fall Apart it was a rushed high school read, just another item in a long list of assignments. The second time, in a compelling college class about postcolonial literature, we deliberately dissected every chapter, line, and Igbo word. In a different English class about trauma, we read Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie’s Half of a Yellow Sun, which paints a wild, tragic portrait of the Nigerian civil war from 1967-1970.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The idiot</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-idiot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-idiot/</guid>
      <description>The first sentence of Bush, Jean Edward Smith’s biography of George W. Bush, obliterates any pretense of objectivity: “Rarely in the history of the United States has the nation been so ill-served as during the presidency of George W. Bush.” The sentence is bracing, somehow — even shocking. We expect our presidential biographers to speak in hushed, respectful tones, partly out of deference to the power of the office and partly because presidential biographies are such dense works demanding so much research that a biographer can suffer from a kind of Stockholm syndrome, developing a fond personal connection that dulls the edge of any criticism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A self-made man</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-self-made-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 13:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-self-made-man/</guid>
      <description>What is it about orphans and literature? Why do so many narratives so dearly love a parentless child, from Moses to the novels of Dickens on down to Batman? On an instinctual level, it seems obvious: parents are shorthand for comfort, and security, and rules, which are three elements that are not conducive to great storytelling. And nothing hypnotizes some readers like the myth of the self-made man, the protagonist who truly doesn’t need anyone else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You down with RBG?</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/you-down-with-rbg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 11:55:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/you-down-with-rbg/</guid>
      <description>Supreme Court Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg, surely familiar now with adoring internet coverage of her dissents, her turns of phrase, her fancy collars, her meme status, made headlines earlier this month in a new and entirely surprising way: She was chastised widely by those on the right and the left for impropriety, after criticizing Donald Trump in interviews. For someone whose status as a hero and internet star is just a few years old, and whose prior reputation was as someone quiet, moderate, and exceedingly proper, this must have been an odd reversal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The one where we talk about books and sitcoms</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-one-where-we-talk-about-books-and-sitcoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-one-where-we-talk-about-books-and-sitcoms/</guid>
      <description>More than ten years after going off the air, NBC’s sitcom Friends still enjoys an enormous influence in popular culture. It’s still regular grist for Buzzfeed, it’s still Taylor Swift’s favorite show, and last year Netflix reportedly dropped around $120 million for streaming rights. Like the Clintons and boy bands, it’s an artifact of the nineties that, for better or worse, stuck around.
No doubt Chandler, Joey, Monica, Phoebe, Rachel, and Ross owe their longevity to an ingenious alchemy of marketing and lifestyle branding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The skin of the unconscious, ripped open</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-skin-of-the-unconscious-ripped-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 12:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-skin-of-the-unconscious-ripped-open/</guid>
      <description>For better or worse — and I would say for better, and worse — there’s only one city that’s truly felt like home to me, and that’s San Francisco. The first time it felt this way was in 1994, and that had a lot to do with JoAnne. We taught each other to breathe and to chew, basic survival skills that we didn’t have because we had to survive, I’m quoting my first novel here, so you see how fiction can offer the truth, I don’t have to use quotation marks because I wrote it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short on pages, long on ideas</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/short-on-pages-long-on-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 13:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/short-on-pages-long-on-ideas/</guid>
      <description>“Life moves fast — books should too,” promises a promotional website for mega-bestselling author James Patterson’s new line of branded mini-novels. BookShots are Patterson’s take on the genre novella, a slick package intended to appeal to Twitter-friendly attention spans. BookShots.com promises that each of the thrillers and romances under the BookShot umbrella will be “Under 150 pages. Under $5. Impossible to put down,” and in case the breathless copy doesn’t get the point across, the site features a 30-second ad featuring a Patrick Bateman-looking young man being chased through the streets of a big city as he reads a BookShot:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The universal darling</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-universal-darling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-universal-darling/</guid>
      <description>In the play Le Demi-Monde by Alexandre Dumas (the younger), he describes a parallel universe in 19th century France where older, married women spend their time in a swirl of seduction, dazzling parties, and opportunism. It was an ode to that epitome of Epicureanism, where a lux libertine lifestyle was the new moral standard and swashbuckling Lotharios oozed charm, no matter their age. But Dumas would not have known that the title of his play would come to characterize an entire lifestyle for the next few decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jealousy and gluttony</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/jealousy-and-gluttony/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 10:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/jealousy-and-gluttony/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes a book will get lost in the depths of a nightstand table for months at a time. That was the case with Leanne Shapton’s Was She Pretty?, a comic which came out earlier this year and then was promptly lost in the stack of books that rests about six inches away from my sleeping head. In a fit of too-late spring cleaning pique, I finally excavated the book last week and read it in one big thirsty gulp, only to find that it is too good to be lost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The poet next door</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-poet-next-door/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 12:57:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-poet-next-door/</guid>
      <description>Here’s the deal: you are perfectly welcome to tell me that you hate poetry, as long as I’m allowed to hit you upside the head with a copy of Hannah Faith Notess’s collection The Multitude in response.
I’m asking permission to assault you with her book because Notess’s work effectively counters every single one of your arguments against poetry. You say you don’t like poetry because you think it’s too vague?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The visible women</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-visible-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 10:58:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-visible-women/</guid>
      <description>![](/webhook-uploads/1467098855693/IMG_0367.JPG)
“We fucking won,” Amelia Bonow announced last night on the corner of 10th and Pike. The crowd around her burst into applause and victorious whoops. These dozens of people had gathered to celebrate the Supreme Court decision that struck down onerous abortion clinic restrictions in Texas. The 5-3 decision, which was delivered a little over twelve hours before the street party, was one of the biggest wins for a woman&amp;rsquo;s right to choose since Roe V Wade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rational Exuberance</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/rational-exuberance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 12:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/rational-exuberance/</guid>
      <description>Every Mary Roach book is crammed full of fascinating characters. In the course of her pop science investigations (Stiff: The Curious Lives of Human Cadavers; Spook: Science Tackles the Afterlife; Bonk: The Curious Coupling of Science and Sex; Packing for Mars: The Curious Science of Life in the Void; and Gulp: Adventures on the Alimentary Canal) Roach often interviews the kind of obsessive minds who used to be referred to as “eccentrics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor of love</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/labor-of-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 13:15:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/labor-of-love/</guid>
      <description>As highly socialized apes, we are fascinated by human interactions. We’re attuned to conflicts, and conflict resolution, and bargaining, and all manner of seduction. And we love to read about all those things in our fiction. Why, then, aren’t there more books about union organizers? People who organize labor see the gamut of human emotion: greed, hope, disappointment, rage. Their job is to get a large number of people to do something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If you ain’t ever been to the ghetto</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/if-you-aint-ever-been-to-the-ghetto/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/if-you-aint-ever-been-to-the-ghetto/</guid>
      <description>If you ain’t ever been to the ghetto
Don’t ever come to the ghetto
‘Cause you wouldn’t understand the ghetto
And stay the fuck out of the ghetto
&#34;Everything’s Gonna Be Alright&#34; (1991), Naughty by Nature
  Mitchell Duneier’s Ghetto: The Invention of a Place, the History of an Idea uses the stories of prominent sociologists to trace the etymology and usage of a single word: “ghetto.”
If you don’t understand the ghetto, Duneier’s book might not be your best starting point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The one-sided deal</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-one-sided-deal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 12:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-one-sided-deal/</guid>
      <description>For many years, I had an agreement with Jhumpa Lahiri. Well, it wasn’t so much an agreement because she never agreed to it. In any case, it went like this: for as long as Lahiri would write fiction and novels, I would read them. In my mind, Lahiri was embarking down the road to a long and fulfilling career, like a Philip Roth or a John Updike, and I was prepared to read all her new books as they came out, to expand my understanding of her writing one book at a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The final frontier</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-final-frontier/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 11:58:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-final-frontier/</guid>
      <description>It’s perhaps a gross generalization to say that most novelists don’t understand quantum physics, but it is a generalization that I feel confident standing behind. You’ll see certain well-worn scientific oversimplifications dragged out again and again in fiction: the idea of light being both particle and wave, depending on how you observe it; the fact that gravity is dependent on mass; and the idea that there are countless parallel universes out there, a multiverse where every world you can imagine is true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sancocho</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/sancocho/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/sancocho/</guid>
      <description>I was a kindergartener in 1958 when the in loco parentis doctrine, which granted teachers the same rights as parents to punish children in their care, was still common practice. It allowed my mean-eyed teacher with the heavily penciled eyebrows and too-black hair to take it upon herself to line up every child in the classroom and inspect our underwear. Someone had pooped their pants and the hapless offender would not, could not, face the humiliation of such a public admission &amp;mdash; at least not voluntarily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five reviews in different styles of Rufi Thorpe&#39;s brilliant new novel</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/five-reviews-in-different-styles-of-rufi-thorpes-brilliant-new-novel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 11:58:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/five-reviews-in-different-styles-of-rufi-thorpes-brilliant-new-novel/</guid>
      <description>THE NEWSPAPER STYLE REVIEW Rufi Thorpe&amp;rsquo;s startling sophomore release, Dear Fang, With Love, which is being released tomorrow, May 24th, brings to mind Roger Ebert&amp;rsquo;s edict about films: they aren&amp;rsquo;t what they&amp;rsquo;re about, but how they&amp;rsquo;re about them.
Not that the what here isn&amp;rsquo;t compelling: a teenage girl, Vera, and her father, Lucas, and a trip they take to Vilnius in Lithuania to trace his familial history, and to get away, in some sense, from dealing with a recent diagnosis of Vera&amp;rsquo;s bi-polar disorder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This machine kills _______ists.</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/this-machine-kills-_______ists/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/this-machine-kills-_______ists/</guid>
      <description>Going into this book, I was feeling extremely prejudiced against standard-issue American singer-songwriter guitar music. Especially traditional stuff. We’re inundated in Seattle. And Woody Guthrie: I get it. He was a socialist protest singer. He was down with the Popular Front in the 1940s. He called his guitar a machine. He meant for it to kill fascists. We would vote Woody Guthrie onto our city council if we could. The songs he wrote still currently catch hella burn at coffeeshops citywide, and on KEXP he’s always there, thanks to the Wilco/Billy Bragg “Mermaid Avenue” record from 18 years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Wonderland is a body</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/your-wonderland-is-a-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 13:19:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/your-wonderland-is-a-body/</guid>
      <description>One of the pleasures of a short story collection is finding the threads that connect the stories. Even if they don’t share characters, or a common continuity, the stories all spring from the same churning subconscious, and so they always carry some DNA-deep similarities. On the surface, the stories in Spokane author Sam Ligon’s Wonderland don’t have much in common: one or two are steeped in realism, another is a retelling of a nursery rhyme, a couple read like longish dirty jokes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Derrick noir</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/derrick-noir/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/derrick-noir/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Imagine a Segway that could kill you and set your house on fire. That’s what a jetpack is.&amp;rdquo; Madeline Ashby&amp;rsquo;s blog post from May of last year &amp;ldquo;No one cares about your jetpack: on optimism in futurism&amp;rdquo; was my introduction to her writing. It&amp;rsquo;s a stellar way to meet someone. Ashby is a science fiction writer, and a card-carrying (whereby card I mean Master&amp;rsquo;s diploma) futurist. She works as someone who thinks about the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go West, young woman</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/go-west-young-woman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/go-west-young-woman/</guid>
      <description>Are you interested in Lindy West the person? Or are you interested in the feminist issues Lindy West frequently discusses, such as fat acceptance? That answer will tell you how much you’ll enjoy her new book Shrill.
I went into Shrill expecting a book making the case for feminist causes. As a professional, West is primarily known for that work, such as her wildly viral Jezebel piece, “How to Make a Rape Joke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It begins with a single step</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/it-begins-with-a-single-step/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 11:58:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/it-begins-with-a-single-step/</guid>
      <description>On Saturdays, I go for Really Long Walks. I’ve been doing this for so long now that it’s become a necessary part of my weekly routine; if I don’t get a Really Long Walk in on a Saturday, I’m miserable and antsy and annoyed for all the next week. Twenty thousand steps, or roughly ten miles, is the bare minimum, but I’m usually happiest if I can squeeze double that into a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real life superhero</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/real-life-superhero/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 13:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/real-life-superhero/</guid>
      <description>The fifteenth annual Free Comic Book Day (FCBD) is this coming Saturday. If you’ve never heard of FCBD before, that’s terrific — you just identified yourself as FCBD’s target audience. It’s exactly what it sounds like: you can wander into your nearest comic book store (find the address at freecomicbookday.com) and walk out with a handful of free comic books, no strings attached.
Say you pick up some comics on FCBD, and you like them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wherein the collector puts his passions on display</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/wherein-the-collector-puts-his-passions-on-display/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/wherein-the-collector-puts-his-passions-on-display/</guid>
      <description>Ricky Jay is a collector. If you&amp;rsquo;ve followed his career, even in periphery, you know that his magic, his acting, his public masquerade are but spokes on the hub of his true passion: the acquisition, study, and understanding of rare magical and performatory tomes, ephemera, and lore. Mr. Jay is a scholar of such, but he is not an academic or bound to an institution apart from one of his own making.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What she thought, but did say</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/what-she-thought-but-did-say/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/what-she-thought-but-did-say/</guid>
      <description>You never stop reciting certain lines from certain poems. Whether battered into your head through schoolroom platforms, or the kind of reading every poetry lover experiences: reading, and then that heart-stopping feeling of your mind bending to the poet&amp;rsquo;s will. The special effects in the movie Inception are familiar to the poetry lover, we feel that world spin every now and again.
And that spin turns into mantra, the quoted line a straight shot to a pattern of synaptic syntactic firing, a shorthand for the feeling: comfort, curiosity, wonder, regret.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open faced</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/open-faced/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 11:43:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/open-faced/</guid>
      <description>The Face is a new series of book-length essays centered around an interesting theme: in each volume, an author writes about their own face. It’s an idea that at once seems expansive as the horizon and as claustrophobic as a broom closet. When meeting strangers, we look to their face for hints of inner character, but we also chastise people for being too narcissistic if they seem overly obsessed with their own appearance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A sprouting Cascadian canon</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-sprouting-cascadian-canon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 13:17:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-sprouting-cascadian-canon/</guid>
      <description>Since August of 2014, co-founders Connor Guy and Alex Davis-Lawrence have published Moss, a self-described “Online Journal of the Northwest,” for free at mosslit.com. It’s a literary magazine that publishes quality longform fiction and non-fiction from, and interviews with, Northwest writers. Last week, Davis-Lawrence and Guy, announced that they were bringing on Spokane novelist Sharma Shields — author of the excellent The Sasquatch Hunter&amp;rsquo;s Almanac — as a contributing editor, with a few more editors yet to be added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poking at death with a long stick</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/poking-at-death-with-a-long-stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/poking-at-death-with-a-long-stick/</guid>
      <description>It’s a hateful job, delivering news of death: the fact of its very existence, its unexpected arrival, its sudden probability. It’s heavy enough just to describe how it feels for the whole idea to swirl in, like a loaded paintbrush tainting the water in a jar. In her latest memoir, What Comes Next and How to Like It, released in paperback today, Abigail Thomas reluctantly and humanely shoulders the job, “just poking at death with a long stick to see what happens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Celebrate a Calendrical Coincidence</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/how-to-celebrate-a-calendrical-coincidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/how-to-celebrate-a-calendrical-coincidence/</guid>
      <description>I stop at Mercer Street Books to pick up the review copy of Lunatics, Lovers and Poets. Where to read it? Which restaurant? Where? Too many cars, too loud, I don’t want to cross the street. Irish pub? No, it’s too dark, too much dark wood, in the middle of our block I avoid the selva oscura. Floyd’s! Floyd’s? It’s gone! How about Mecca, that’ll work, but that’s all the way round.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There&#39;s something about Mary</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/theres-something-about-mary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 11:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/theres-something-about-mary/</guid>
      <description>Canadian cartoonist Chester Brown reads from his new book *Mary Wept Over the Feet of Jesus: Prostitution and Religious Obedience in the Bible* on [Saturday, April 16th at 7 pm at the Hugo House](https://hugohouse.org/event/book-party-for-chester-browns-mary-wept-over-the-feet-of-jesus/). Both of the *Seattle Review of Books* co-founders, Paul Constant and Martin McClellan, read the book, and it left them with a lot of conflicted feelings. The following is a conversation they had on a Google Doc as they tried to determine what it was about *Mary* that left them feeling so strangely dissatisfied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Please note that we didn&#39;t publish this review at 4:20</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/please-note-that-we-didnt-publish-this-review-at-420/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 11:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/please-note-that-we-didnt-publish-this-review-at-420/</guid>
      <description>Humans have enjoyed marijuana for about 12,000 years. It is now recreationally legal in four states and medically legal in roughly half of the country. In America, 18.9 million have sparked a joint in the past 30 days.
I first sampled the wonders of weed while attending San Rafael High School, the northern California institution of learning that introduced the term “420” to the popular vernacular in the early 1970s. Over the ensuing decades, I have enjoyed a steady relationship with the kind herb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The man who paints tigers on an island</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-man-who-paints-tigers-on-an-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-man-who-paints-tigers-on-an-island/</guid>
      <description>Singapore is especially difficult for Westerners to understand. People who visit come back like a blind man from the parable of the elephant, convinced that the trunk they felt represents the whole of the place.
Infamously, William Gibson wondered where the underground was when he visited in 1993 and wrote his Wired essay &amp;ldquo;Disneyland with the Death Penalty&amp;rdquo;. He lamented, among other things, the loss of the red light district.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give me a G-R-E-E-N-W-O-O-D! </title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/give-me-a-g-r-e-e-n-w-o-o-d-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/give-me-a-g-r-e-e-n-w-o-o-d-/</guid>
      <description>Every good story gets the timing right. In the case of the brand-new Encyclopedia Greenwoodia &amp;mdash; a collection of prose, poetry, and images by, for, and about Seattle’s Greenwood neighborhood &amp;mdash; timing is the story.
For more than a decade, the Greater Seattle Bureau of Fearless Ideas (BFI; formerly 826 Seattle), a Greenwood-based youth writing and tutoring center, has produced annual volumes written by students, occasionally together with adult mentors and author friends of the nonprofit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you there, whoever? It&#39;s me, Lesley</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/are-you-there-whoever-its-me-lesley/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 14:24:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/are-you-there-whoever-its-me-lesley/</guid>
      <description>“Consider: A stranger calls you on the phone, says she’s conducting a survey, and asks if you believe in God,” Lesley Hazleton writes near the beginning of her new book. “You can answer only yes or no, since don’t knows don’t count. And consider too that if you simply hang up, as you’re likely to do if you consider this an absurdly simplistic question, you don’t count either.” Hazleton is explaining why polls usually indicate that Americans are such devout believers in God; if you force someone to make a binary choice, all nuance and shading simply disappears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The virtues of Patience</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-virtues-of-patience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 13:03:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-virtues-of-patience/</guid>
      <description>In 1994, Dan Clowes had recently completed his first attempt at a longform comic story, the surrealistic Like a Velvet Glove Cast in Iron, and he had just embarked on his most realistic story to date, Ghost World. If you were to tap a Clowes fan on the shoulder in those days and tell her that in the future, Clowes would create a graphic novel that identifies him visually as an heir to superhero comics icons Jack Kirby and Steve Ditko, she would either laugh at you, tell you you’re making shit up, or inform you that strangers tapping her on the shoulder and making weird predictions in public places make her very uncomfortable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Written under the influence</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/written-under-the-influence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/written-under-the-influence/</guid>
      <description>In an essay called “On Pandering,” author Claire Vaye Watkins claims that, for her entire career, she has been unconsciously assimilating the values of the prejudiced, male-dominated literary community. “I wanted to write something Cormac McCarthy would like,” she says, “something Thomas Pynchon would come out of hiding to endorse, something David Foster Wallace would blurb from beyond the grave.” This is coming from the author of the award winning story collection Battleborn, which takes the following as its subjects: young parents embracing the idea of having a child, teenage girls navigating sexual abuse, foreigners in Nevada brothels, gold prospectors, and the Manson Family commune.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saved from the flames of history</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/saved-from-the-flames-of-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 16:56:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/saved-from-the-flames-of-history/</guid>
      <description>When Seattle novelist Bharti Kirchner was growing up in Kolkata, she writes in the afterword to her new novel Goddess of Fire, she “yearned to learn more about Job Charnock, a faithful servant of the English East India Company in its early days, who was believed to have founded Kolkata (then known as Calcutta).” But not much information about Charnock has survived from 17th century India to the present day. So Kirchner spent a lifetime obsessing over the few facts available, including an account that Charnock saved a young Indian girl from being tossed onto her deceased husband’s funeral pyre, and eventually married her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>...in love and war</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/in-love-and-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 11:52:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/in-love-and-war/</guid>
      <description>All poetry is political.
This is not to say that poetry is an especially political form. All poetry is political because all poetry is created by people, and all people are political animals.
And, yes, in fact, poetry is whatever people are: political, sure — but also loving, spiteful, awkward, romantic, horny, judgmental, and overly obsessed with our little glowing screens.
So I guess what I’m saying here is that all poetry is horny.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everybody&#39;s straightening like it&#39;s a commercial</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/everybodys-straightening-like-its-a-commercial/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/everybodys-straightening-like-its-a-commercial/</guid>
      <description>Marie Kondo is the gentle ruler of an empire built on a most unusual foundation. Her Life-Changing Magic of Tidying Up: The Japanese Art of Decluttering and Organizing, published in the US in 2014, is still at the top of the New York Times bestseller list &amp;mdash; right above her just-released Spark Joy. She was one of _Time Magazine_’s People of the Year in 2015. Her immense popularity has drawn coverage in the New York Times, the Atlantic, and countless articles and blog posts &amp;mdash; both adulating and irritated &amp;mdash; across the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And everything a scenic view</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/and-everything-a-scenic-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 12:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/and-everything-a-scenic-view/</guid>
      <description>…Look, a cat killed a cardinal
on an emerald lawn.
For so many reasons it shouldn’t have been beautiful. But that’s also
the kind of book
I like best.  Looking, according to Lia Purpura, is always instructive. She describes what she finds, and how it registers in her body. Feelings that are complicated, hard to pin down, uncomfortable or confusing call her to deeper inquiry. She’s refined her practice through three collections of essays (Increase, Rough Likeness, and On Looking,) and three of poetry (The Brighter the Veil, Stone Sky Lifting, and King Baby).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A city holds its breath</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-city-holds-its-breath/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 10:23:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-city-holds-its-breath/</guid>
      <description>A city is not just a black dot on a map. A city is not just its streets, or its buildings, or its people. When you take a long view, a city is a river in time. If you were to view the life of a city from its founding to its destruction in high speed, say a year passing every second, you would see it as a jittery flow of kinetic energy that wends and winds and shapes the earth around it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staring across a border, looking at a wall</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/staring-across-a-border-looking-at-a-wall/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/staring-across-a-border-looking-at-a-wall/</guid>
      <description>Donald Trump wants to build a wall and make Mexico pay for it. It will be a beauty. He builds nice fences. Fences are easy. Will Donald’s beautiful wall replace the billions of dollars of fencing that has already been erected along parts of the 1,933-mile border interspersed with a &amp;ldquo;virtual&amp;rdquo; fence of cameras and sensors? Or will it merely fill in the gaps, some of which experts have already determined to be hazardous to workers, environmentally devastating, or prohibitively expensive?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Adverbs of War</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-adverbs-of-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 11:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-adverbs-of-war/</guid>
      <description>The title of Seattle poet Don Mee Choi’s second book, Hardly War, is a curious combination of words that seems innocuous enough if you’re, say, skimming spines on a bookshelf. But if you give it two seconds’ thought, those two words, “hardly” and “war,” obviously belong nowhere near each other. War is a binary; you’re either at war or you’re not. There are no small wars, or halfway wars, or hardly wars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drawn this way</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/drawn-this-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/drawn-this-way/</guid>
      <description>In the beginning was the author. She wrote into a blank void, empty of human emotion, empty of human intention. There, she placed the character, who stood looking around and scratching herself occasionally.
The author gave the character a desire, and the character moved. She moved towards her yearning, and in her movement a path was created, spanning from the point she started all the way to the point that contained her desire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The writer we deserve</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-writer-we-deserve/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-writer-we-deserve/</guid>
      <description>It’s early in the year, time for taking on ambitious, resolution-worthy reading projects, and what better project than The Dying Grass, the latest novel from William T. Vollmann?
Vollmann, our young nation’s own Tolstoy.
Russia can keep Count Lev Nikolaevich and his high society, literary friends, peasant pedagogy, and pacifist moralism. Oh look, there’s Leo dressing up as a muzhik again.
Here in the modern-day U.S.A., we’ve got William Tanner Vollmann.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whose streets? Our streets!</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/whose-streets-our-streets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 10:07:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/whose-streets-our-streets/</guid>
      <description>In 2008, the Seattle International Film Festival hosted the film Battle in Seattle as its opening night gala presentation. Battle, a fictionalized account of the 1999 World Trade Organization protests, had the pedigree of a successful film: it starred Charlize Theron, Outkast’s Andre 3000, Woody Harrelson, Ray Liotta, and Channing Tatum, and it was scored by Massive Attack. At the opening night screening, the room clearly wanted to be on the film&amp;rsquo;s side; Seattle desperately loves to see itself legitimized through adaptation, even if nine times out of ten it’s portrayed onscreen by Vancouver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The book was better, but the movie was shorter</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-book-was-better-but-the-movie-was-shorter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 11:57:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-book-was-better-but-the-movie-was-shorter/</guid>
      <description>You probably haven’t read The Scarlet Letter since you were in high school. That’s understandable. Most people recall The Scarlet Letter as an arduous reading experience. This is because The Scarlet Letter is not a book that should be given to teenagers. Its themes — of responsibility to the community, of the simultaneous importance and uselessness of personal reputation, of id and ego — are way too sincere and nuanced for any hormone-addled teenager to understand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Across the transverse</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/across-the-transverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/across-the-transverse/</guid>
      <description>&#34;The hard part was sorting it all out. The hard part was taking a good look at everyone else and the way they looked at the world, which was a lot different than the way _I_ was looking the world.&#34; - Kate Bornstein, *Gender Outlaw*.  &#34;What if we&#39;re not trapped in the wrong body, but trapped in the wrong society?&#34; - Juliet Jacques There&#39;s an old Benny Hill sketch where his randy simple-minded character is walking down the street, behind a blonde with luxurious long hair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caught after dark in Lovecraft Country</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/caught-after-dark-in-lovecraft-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/caught-after-dark-in-lovecraft-country/</guid>
      <description>Matt Ruff had me a few pages into his new novel, Lovecraft Country, where one of its black characters ponders my own great childhood shame this way: “Tom Swift &amp;hellip; which Earl had loved when he was young … embarrassed him now, both for the books’ depiction of Negroes and for the fact that as a boy he hadn’t noticed it &amp;hellip;.” Because Ruff’s book has the mid-1950s as its setting, Earl almost certainly refers to the original series of Swift novels, which predate WWI and even have a white character use the expression “nigger in the woodpile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Songs are not poems in fancy clothing</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/songs-are-not-poems-in-fancy-clothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 12:01:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/songs-are-not-poems-in-fancy-clothing/</guid>
      <description>I love Simon Joyner’s music already — I don’t listen to it all the time, or even every year, though I always come back — but I was unsure about this collection. Lyrics are not, I think, “poems without their clothing,” as Dennis Callaci writes in his introduction to Only Love Can Bring You Peace, Joyner&amp;rsquo;s first book. Dudes: poems are not naked songs. Not everything is purer, more vulnerable when stripped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time out of joint</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/time-out-of-joint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 11:53:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/time-out-of-joint/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s gauche, I know, for a reviewer to ask a favor of his readers. In 2016, a book critic should be happy to be read at all. But I’m going to ask something of you, regardless — and hopefully you’ll get something out of this, too, besides the glow of internal warmth that comes from knowing that you indulged the whims of a tired old book reviewer. My request is this: print this review out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncommitted</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/uncommitted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/uncommitted/</guid>
      <description>In 1860, Mrs. Elizabeth Packard had a conversation with a traveling sewing machine salesman. Her husband, a Calvinist minister named Theophilus Packard, was on her mind. Elizabeth had recently caused quite a ruckus when she stood up in the middle of one of her husband&amp;rsquo;s sermons, and announced that she was crossing the street to the Presbyterian church, whose religious views aligned better with hers.
&amp;ldquo;She found fault that Mr. Packard would not discuss their points of difference in religion in an open manly way instead of going around and denouncing her as crazy to her friends and to the church,&amp;rdquo; the salesman later testified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A rainbow of grief</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-rainbow-of-grief/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 11:54:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-rainbow-of-grief/</guid>
      <description>If you hold a copy of Tom Hart’s new graphic novel Rosalie Lightning away from you by the spine, here is what you’ll see:
![](/webhook-uploads/1453965563321/RosalieLightning.jpg)
The pages are stratified in asymmetrical bands of black and white — thick stretches of white broken up by occasional, quick bursts of black, with one dense stand of black pages. You see this kind of striation in black-and-white comics collections all the time, but in Rosalie Lightning, it looks more portentous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Body of work</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/body-of-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 11:57:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/body-of-work/</guid>
      <description>In The Argonauts, Maggie Nelson seeks to clear things up by muddling them, by sweeping a careful hand through our delicate Manichean constructs of what’s gay, trans, queer, female, and more. In a mixture of memoir and critical meditation, Nelson recounts her relationship with her partner Harry Dodge, her efforts to become pregnant, and the birth of her son, Iggy, using the quotidian tools of family-building to pick apart our words and notions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Punk snot dead</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/punk-snot-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/punk-snot-dead/</guid>
      <description>Maire M. Masco, publisher of Seattle&amp;rsquo;s 1981 punk rock newspaper Desperate Times, had to consult her own copy to define “donut-holer” &amp;mdash; an epithet from the first issue and a few more down the line. Masco for the record:
“At 1st and Pike, the entrance to the Pike Place Market, was a notorious donut shop. The place was open 24 hours a day and particularly after dark, was full of drunks, derelicts and street people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a lovely way to burn</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/what-a-lovely-way-to-burn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 11:56:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/what-a-lovely-way-to-burn/</guid>
      <description>We live in a dystopian future in which the publishing industry puts out way too many works of dystopian fiction. The shelves of bookstores — young adult sections most especially — are packed to bursting with futures in which teenagers are forced to do battle for the amusement of the wealthy one percent, or in which a grizzled band of people who have seen too many bad things are trying to make their way to the mythical land of California, or in which Donald Trump is on the verge of winning the Republican presidential nomination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> “The idea of freedom might be too great a temptation for them to resist&#34;</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/-the-idea-of-freedom-might-be-too-great-a-temptation-for-them-to-resist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 16:01:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/-the-idea-of-freedom-might-be-too-great-a-temptation-for-them-to-resist/</guid>
      <description>A sudden flurry of outraged tweets and blog posts last week led me to A Birthday Cake for George Washington, written by Ramin Ganeshram and illustrated by Vanessa Brantley-Newton, which the publisher touted as “based on real events.” Set in 1790s Philadelphia, where George Washington was serving as America’s first president, the story is about Hercules, Washington’s slave-cook, and is narrated by his young daughter Delia.
Last night, less than two weeks after releasing the book (and only hours after I read it), Scholastic withdrew it and released this statement:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laid bear</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/laid-bear/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 12:01:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/laid-bear/</guid>
      <description>Let’s lay it out as simply as possible: Marian Engel’s Bear is a novel about a woman who has an erotic relationship with a bear. As you can imagine, this is the sort of premise that probably makes book cover artists lick their lips with anticipation.
![](/webhook-uploads/1452487751509/PaperbackCoverofBearbyMarianEngel.jpg)
To the left of this paragraph, you’ll see the 1976 book cover for the paperback release of Bear. It is, as promotional materials for a newer edition of the book claim, “Heavy Metal-inspired,&amp;rdquo; which is to say that it is lurid and shocking and fun, and also aimed directly at the adolescent male gaze.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delicious nothingness</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/delicious-nothingness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 13:01:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/delicious-nothingness/</guid>
      <description>On Monday of this week, a video went viral. If you’ve been on the internet at all, you probably saw it in one iteration or another, be it .gif or Vine or remixed music video: a raccoon is slavering over a brick of cotton candy. Being a raccoon, it goes to wash the cotton candy in a nearby pool of water. Being cotton candy, the block disintegrates as soon as the raccoon dips it in the water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Nick Licata won Seattle politics</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/how-nick-licata-won-seattle-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 11:45:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/how-nick-licata-won-seattle-politics/</guid>
      <description>Today, Nick Licata is retiring from the Seattle City Council after four terms. He leaves behind a very impressive legacy. Licata was the most progressive member of the council at a time when Seattle was experimenting with a very prickly east coast version of urbanism, exemplified by Mark Sidran’s atrocious civility laws and Joe Mallahan’s dumb corporate paternalism. And the council that is being sworn in today is more liberal, in part, because of Licata’s tireless advocacy for liberal causes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Years Day</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/new-years-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 10:02:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/new-years-day/</guid>
      <description>After Thanksgiving, New Years Day is my favorite holiday. Unlike the gifts of Christmas or the costumes of Halloween, New Year’s Day brings with it no obligations. You’re just supposed to relax, and not work, and think about the year that just ended and the year that just began. If you’re hungover, maybe the day is about regret. If you’ve made a series of resolutions, maybe it’s about hope. But it’s a day that is profoundly uninterested in itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another day, another blockbuster</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/another-day-another-blockbuster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 10:02:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/another-day-another-blockbuster/</guid>
      <description>Even the most complimentary reviews of Star Wars: The Force Awakens mention that the movie is for all intents and purposes a remake of Star Wars: A New Hope. Critics who loved the film tended to refer to the fact that it’s a remake as an aside; critics who disliked the film based their entire reviews around it. This is not automatically a strike against Force so much as a reality of moviemaking today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ballad of Richard Milhous Nixon</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-ballad-of-richard-milhous-nixon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 09:54:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-ballad-of-richard-milhous-nixon/</guid>
      <description>“With respect, I’m as good a man as Kennedy,” Vice President Richard Nixon tells Dwight Eisenhower. But his boss is having none of it. Ike spits back:
“You’re a climbing little rat. The way you went after Hiss, the way you’ve got on TV and spilled your guts, the way you begged for it. You’re bent, Dick. You were by a long way the sorriest son of a bitch I could get for the job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broken toys</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/broken-toys/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 12:03:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/broken-toys/</guid>
      <description>The children of a candidate for a statewide position are kidnapped by a death cult. The candidate, not wanting a high-profile media investigation so close to election day, hires a pair of investigators to quietly bring his kids back. From there, things get ugly.
That’s the plot of Nelly Reifler’s most recent novel. The catch is that the candidate and his children are mice, and the investigators the candidate hires are Barbie and Ken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Doctor is in</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-doctor-is-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 10:05:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-doctor-is-in/</guid>
      <description>I’m not a Whovian. I’ve seen and enjoyed a few episodes of the Doctor Who season where the Doctor was played by Christopher Eccleston, but I don’t have the patience to immerse myself in the dense continuity and playful self-indulgence of Doctor Who fandom. The hours I contribute to television-watching are relatively few, and I tend to be a completist about these sorts of things. I don’t have enough hours in my life to contribute to the cause of watching all the Doctor Who episodes out there floating around the streaming sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The sky is falling</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-sky-is-falling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 11:45:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-sky-is-falling/</guid>
      <description>![](/webhook-uploads/1450162683243/Screen%20Shot%202015-12-14%20at%2010.57.19%20PM.png)
Zombies, zombies everywhere. Who the hell isn’t a little sick of zombies at this point? Even people who love carnage and a little fictional gunplay ought to be getting sick of zombies by now, right? You can stretch the metaphor like a wad of chewing gum — the zombies stand for consumerism, or they represent our germ-phobia, or they represent our self-loathing — but eventually that thin pink strand is gonna break.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What the heart wants</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/what-the-heart-wants/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 12:01:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/what-the-heart-wants/</guid>
      <description>If you’re a human being with a working heart, you will cry when you read The Best Party of Our Lives1. Likely multiple times. Sarah Galvin’s2 collection of interviews with same-sex couples about their weddings is a goddamned happy-tear factory. Whether you prefer to read stories of old couples or young couples; whirlwind romances or thoughtful, long relationships; couples with opposite interests or couples who are practically clones of each other; you’ll find a pairing here that speaks to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Un-perfumed letters</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/un-perfumed-letters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/un-perfumed-letters/</guid>
      <description>Words in Air, the correspondence between Elizabeth Bishop and Robert Lowell, is one of the books I’m never entirely not reading. I pick it up all the time, and it’s always better than I remembered. There is a unique effect of these writers, their letters soothe my mind, the way the exact right word can be both calming and exciting no matter the topic. Their letters make being a person seem like a reasonable way to spend time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows into the future</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/windows-into-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/windows-into-the-future/</guid>
      <description>The jokes write themselves. Shortly after the publication of Future Visions: Science Fiction Stories Inspired By Microsoft, a friend posted a graphic about it. In the image, Clippy, the infamous animated paperclip/Microsoft Office assistant, is saying, &amp;ldquo;Hi! It looks like you&amp;rsquo;re trying to dock over Alpha Centauri! May I suggest reverse thrusters?&amp;rdquo;
There&amp;rsquo;s just no way to resist poking fun at any company publishing a book &amp;ldquo;inspired&amp;rdquo; by itself. Imagine &amp;ldquo;Caffeinated Comedy: Knock-Knock Jokes About Starbucks&amp;rsquo; Pumpkin Spice Latte,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Tape-Filled Tomes: Adventure Stories In Which 3M&amp;rsquo;s Post-It Notes Save the Day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crow quill pen and bible black ink</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/crow-quill-pen-and-bible-black-ink/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/crow-quill-pen-and-bible-black-ink/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always wondered how art collectors decide which artists to collect &amp;mdash; not the profit driven monsters who play galleries like traders play the markets, but true fans who love art and emerging artists, who show up early and often, and buy many pieces by new talent. But it dawned me while I read Molly Crabapple&amp;rsquo;s memoir Drawing Blood: they learn the artist&amp;rsquo;s story. When you learn someone&amp;rsquo;s story, you forge an empathetic lock with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michel Houellebecq and the limitations of satire</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/michel-houellebecq-and-the-limitations-of-satire/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 13:06:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/michel-houellebecq-and-the-limitations-of-satire/</guid>
      <description>Michel Houellebecq is a terrible person. He is also, if his translators have done their job correctly, an excellent writer. This isn’t a rarity — plenty of writers are awful people. But unlike many of the worst people who write, Houellebecq doesn’t try to conceal his awfulness. Instead, he revels in it.
Houellebecq has made a career out of provocation. His essay praising H.P. Lovecraft’s ahuman tendencies is probably the best critical reappraisal of Lovecraft ever written.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sitting in the middle of a clock</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/sitting-in-the-middle-of-a-clock/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 11:51:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/sitting-in-the-middle-of-a-clock/</guid>
      <description>See You in the Morning, Mairead Case’s debut novel, is a love story if a love story means trying to become someone who doesn’t always feel shut off. It’s the summer before senior year in high school, and the unnamed narrator is already planning to move away from a town that’s maybe too comfortable or not comfortable enough, not dreamy but not dreary — maybe there aren’t enough options, but what options is this narrator looking for?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The road to Donald Trump is paved with decency</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-road-to-donald-trump-is-paved-with-decency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 13:25:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-road-to-donald-trump-is-paved-with-decency/</guid>
      <description>The introduction to Destiny and Power, the new biography of George H.W. Bush, makes it pretty clear where Jon Meacham’s loyalty as a biographer lies. Bush, Meacham writes, “was driven less by ideas about politics than by an ideal of service and an ambition — a consuming one — to win.” He continues:
Americans unhappy with the reflexively polarized politics of the first decades of the twenty-first century will find the presidency of George H.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The publishers&#39; dilemma</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-publishers-dilemma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 12:01:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-publishers-dilemma/</guid>
      <description>As the co-founder of this site put it in September, we are living in a golden age of publishing. Social media, the Espresso Book Machine and yes, even Amazon’s e-book arm have collapsed the distance between writer and audience, and in some cases entirely circumvented the need for traditional publishers.
In the face of these near-instantaneous platforms, those traditional publishers start to look like hidebound anachronisms, stubbornly inefficient relics from a bygone, pre-digital age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A love letter to Eve Babitz</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-love-letter-to-eve-babitz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2015 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-love-letter-to-eve-babitz/</guid>
      <description>Dear Eve &amp;mdash;
The hardest part of being a writer is seeming natural. It&#39;s the same with actors: I was once in a commercial — an extra off to the side of one scene. The lead actress was doing improv, and when she turned to me and showed a crinkled nose of disgust and spit out some off-the-cuff line, I almost broke character because I thought she just blew the take and was mad at herself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The inventor, viewed in stereo</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-inventor-viewed-in-stereo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-inventor-viewed-in-stereo/</guid>
      <description>We all owned one. My 1970s-era View-Master was red plastic with white trim, and the reels my parents bought for it tended towards the G-rated and Disneyified &amp;mdash; Cinderella, Bambi, maybe an occasional visitor from the Krofft Super Show. (Why were those other sea monsters so mean to Sigmund?)
But my sister, 18 years older than me and the mother of my three nieces, was a young stay-at-home mom on a limited budget who haunted garage sales like it was her job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sex and violence and the sex of violence</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/sex-and-violence-and-the-sex-of-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 12:04:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/sex-and-violence-and-the-sex-of-violence/</guid>
      <description>Anyone looking at a copy of Benjamin Marra’s Terror Assaulter: OMWOT (One Man War on Terror) is forced to do some heavy categorizing. The cover features a guy in a suit, wearing sunglasses, and smoking a cigarette beheading a bad guy with a katana. The bad guy is armed with a gun and a chainsaw, built like the proverbial brick shithouse, and is dressed like an old He-Man figure: blue briefs and a belt, frilly boots, and a little cape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey to prison island</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/journey-to-prison-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 11:54:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/journey-to-prison-island/</guid>
      <description>Some people would argue that forbidden love stories are the only love stories worth telling. The people who would argue that are probably not the kind of people you should date. Sure, a love story can be compelling if parents or society or circumstances deny the lovers from their right to be happy. But not every transgression is a welcome one, and not every love story is innocent.
The titular narrator of Jennifer Tseng’s novel Mayumi and the Sea of Happiness believes that she is in love, and she believes passionately in the love story she’s telling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living up to the best</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/living-up-to-the-best/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 12:29:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/living-up-to-the-best/</guid>
      <description>When you edit a book titled The Best American Comics 2015, you are almost certainly setting yourself up for failure. Surely Jonathan Lethem knew this when he signed on for the job. Worse yet, when he agreed to be the editor of the 2015 edition of The Best American Comics, he must have known he was immediately following Scott McCloud’s entry in the series, which is by far the best Best American Comics to ever see publication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drink to forget, ink to remember</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/drink-to-forget-ink-to-remember/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 11:45:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/drink-to-forget-ink-to-remember/</guid>
      <description>Memoirs are sometimes too much for me to handle, but I can read autobiographical comics all day, every day. So what’s the difference? Ultimately, it’s a matter of scale. You have to suspend a whole lot of belief to cozy up to the idea that a human being’s life coheres exactly to something resembling a narrative arc with a beginning, a middle, and an end — especially when it’s got a pat little moral plugged into the core of the thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short Run: I second that</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/short-run-i-second-that/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/short-run-i-second-that/</guid>
      <description>![](/webhook-uploads/1446528603140/IMG_0698.JPG)
You&amp;rsquo;ve hopefully already read Paul&amp;rsquo;s definitive guide to the Short Run Comix and Arts Festival, but I wanted to share what my more personal experience of what the day was like.
I was with my five year-old, who was pretty excited as soon as he figured out that he could trick &amp;lsquo;r treat at most of the tables, so long as they showed a little pink indicator sign. This was ingenious, so thank you to all of the tables that participated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short Run for the long haul</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/short-run-for-the-long-haul/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 11:56:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/short-run-for-the-long-haul/</guid>
      <description>![](/webhook-uploads/1446445816356/IMG_57hp5s.jpg)
Conventions are strange. We find them appealing because they’re momentary — they exist for a day, or a weekend, and then they’re gone. But we also become attached to specific conventions; we get used to the rhythms and organizational themes, and we get upset when we feel that a convention has “betrayed” its original voice. So we expect conventions to be transitory, but we also demand consistency from convention organizers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not-so-living history</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/not-so-living-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 13:31:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/not-so-living-history/</guid>
      <description>Sarah Vowell is in rare company when it comes to her ability to craft a biting, funny sentence. She’s up against David Sedaris and Jincy Willett and a small handful of other names. Consider this line from her latest book, Lafayette in the Somewhat United States:
“I do not think that there can ever be enough books about anything; and I say that knowing that some of them are going to be about Pilates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That is so weird</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/that-is-so-weird/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/that-is-so-weird/</guid>
      <description>Johanna Sinisalo, fondly known as the queen of Finnish Weird, is coming to Seattle, and will be appearing at the Elliott Bay Book Company on October 24th, and I&amp;rsquo;m quite excited about it. I live in Seattle. Elliott Bay is my neighborhood bookstore. I&amp;rsquo;ve been a fan of Sinisalo&amp;rsquo;s work for years. And I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked to serve as a sort of host, because I translated her two most recent novels into English.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking and seeing are two different things</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/looking-and-seeing-are-two-different-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 13:55:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/looking-and-seeing-are-two-different-things/</guid>
      <description>The title novella in Colum McCann’s new collection Thirteen Ways of Looking is a mystery, but it’s less of a whodunnit and more of a how’d-it-happen. Our protagonist, a former New York state Supreme Court judge named Peter Mendelssohn, is elderly and infirm. His wife, Eileen, has died. His son, Elliot, is a disappointment. Mendelssohn spends all morning in bed, thinking of the life he lived. He’s not overcome with regret, although he desperately hates the adult diaper that his nurse, an immigrant named Sally, makes him wear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Invisible Art of Magazines</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-invisible-art-of-magazines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 13:36:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-invisible-art-of-magazines/</guid>
      <description>Magazines fill a very particular literary void. We read novels for their depth and substance, we read comics to be dazzled, we read poetry collections to be immersed in the brain of a person who sees the world differently than we do. But we read magazines when we want to hear a chorus of voices, when we want to travel, when we need to filter a large expanse of the world through a singular organizational perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collateral Damage</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/collateral-damage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 16:27:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/collateral-damage/</guid>
      <description>Ekia jackpot birds blink baseball cards
Objectives theater footprint transit range
Remotely plotted aircraft finish ops
Persistent stare near certainty sign off
Find fix finish exploit and analyze
Host nation tyranny of distances  The touchdown tyranny of distances
Joint special operations baseball cards
Taking a strike exploit and analyze
Developing a target transit range
Of orbits of watch list kill chain sign off
To authorize the touchdown finish ops  The POTUS actioning the finish ops</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teenage wasteland</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/teenage-wasteland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 12:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/teenage-wasteland/</guid>
      <description>Adolescence is the uncomfortable transition from childhood, when one assumes that one is the center of the universe, to adulthood, when one realizes that this is not true. Just about everything we understand about teenagers makes sense when viewed from this lens — the sense of injustice, the anger, the nihilism. It takes at least a full decade just to get over the horrific realization that the universe will continue without us one day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sorry, Eileen Myles</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/sorry-eileen-myles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 11:44:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/sorry-eileen-myles/</guid>
      <description>It’s the year 2018. In a press conference, NASA scientists have just announced a shocking new discovery. As part of their research into cryogenic sleep for deep-space flights, they have finally uncovered the secret of immortality. At that announcement, the press corps immediately respond with murmuring and more exciteable, goose-like noises, but as the sussuration begins to build into a straight-on frenzy, the lead scientist raises her hands. Wait a minute, she says to the assembled media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One white step closer to the fire</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/one-white-step-closer-to-the-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 11:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/one-white-step-closer-to-the-fire/</guid>
      <description>Having a conversation with white people about race — specifically, about black people in America, inspired, say, by the shooting of Michael Brown or Ta-Nehisi Coates&amp;rsquo; essay on reparations — is easy until you get to one of those words. Privilege, say, or supremacy, or institutional, or, god forbid, reparations. Those words are hard because white people hear them differently than minorities. White people hear &amp;ldquo;privilege&amp;rdquo; and think &amp;ldquo;this person wants me to give up power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make it hurt so good</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/make-it-hurt-so-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/make-it-hurt-so-good/</guid>
      <description>If you’re looking for a book to uplift you, to temporarily alleviate the struggles of your daily life, keep looking. Fates and Furies is a novel of attrition; National Book Award nominee Lauren Groff tears away at her characters as her readers lose faith in them. This marathon of a novel leaves you wondering: was it really worth the pain?
Well, it depends on what you’re into. Born into wealth, Lotto must clear hurdles to impress his mother, a feat he never quite achieves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections by and about white people</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/reflections-by-and-about-white-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/reflections-by-and-about-white-people/</guid>
      <description>Ryan Boudinot’s anthology Seattle: City of Literature: Reflections from a Community of Writers was just released by Sasquatch Books and heralded in a Seattle Met review with this subheading: “The new anthology is a comprehensive snapshot of Seattle’s community of writers, past and present.”
If “comprehensive” means Seattle’s community of mostly white writers, then I suppose the descriptor is accurate. Boudinot in his preface calls the collection “a representative sampling,” which again can only be true if the community from which he is sampling is overwhelmingly white.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A real American hero</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-real-american-hero/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 11:52:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-real-american-hero/</guid>
      <description>Let’s make one thing perfectly clear as we begin: Edward Snowden is an American hero. You may feel differently about the subject of Edward Snowden than I do. If so, I’m going to advise you that you’re perfectly welcome to read the rest of this book review, but it’s probably going to make you mad. I’m probably not going to change your mind and you’re probably not going to change mine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State of the union</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/state-of-the-union/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 11:57:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/state-of-the-union/</guid>
      <description>At one time not so very long ago, American literature was rich with fiction about unions. Robert Cantwell’s Aberdeen-set novel Land of Plenty, which was recently revived by Jess Walter for local publisher Pharos Editions, is a good example of the genre. It makes sense that labor would mesh well with fiction; whenever you get a lot of people together in pursuit of a common goal, all sorts of interesting things happen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Juvenile, detention</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/juvenile-detention/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 12:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/juvenile-detention/</guid>
      <description>Because her parents worked for the penitentiary system, a large part of local cartoonist Colleen Frakes’ youth was spent on McNeil Island, the last prison island in the United States not connected to the mainland by roads. Though McNeil was relatively close to Tacoma on the south Sound, it was still disconnected from civilization in nearly every way; most prison employees lived in a company town on the island and used infrequent ferry service to connect to civilization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The most thoughtful obituary writer in all of southeastern Alaska</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-most-thoughtful-obituary-writer-in-all-of-southeastern-alaska/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2015 11:57:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-most-thoughtful-obituary-writer-in-all-of-southeastern-alaska/</guid>
      <description>At a time when reality TV continues its relentless portrayal of Alaska as a source of extreme and outlandish (even ridiculous) behavior, author Heather Lende consistently reminds readers that it is actually a place populated by people, just like anywhere else. As the newspaper obituary writer for the small town of Haines, (population about 2,000), Lende has written for years about ordinary people who have quietly lived extraordinary lives. She shared some of these stories in her first book, If You Lived Here, I’d Know Your Name and then, after suffering horrific injuries when she was hit by a truck near her home, wrote a memoir of her recovery, Take Good Care of the Garden and the Dogs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intoxicating and irresistible and maybe untrue</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/intoxicating-and-irresistible-and-maybe-untrue/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/intoxicating-and-irresistible-and-maybe-untrue/</guid>
      <description>All writing advice is expendable. It is necessarily incomplete and reflects the advice-giver’s biases and preferences. Such advice can certainly be useful, but it offers only one version of what writing can be. This holds true for Mary Karr’s new book The Art of Memoir, an introduction to her theories about the genre, a compendium of suggestions for writing, and a close look at some of her favorite examples. The beguiling tone and the witty, lively style from her successful memoirs The Liars’ Club, _Cherry, and Lit are on full display in this new book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upstairs, downstairs</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/upstairs-downstairs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 11:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/upstairs-downstairs/</guid>
      <description>Last night, Town Hall hosted Jonathan Franzen in their upstairs Great Hall. You can tell a Franzen crowd from three blocks away — lots of corduroy jackets and elbow patches. That woman yelling at the parking lot attendant because it’ll cost her $8 to park her fancy car in the lot behind Town Hall? Total Franzen person. The miserable-looking bald man in a suit dragging his wife up the sidewalk as she staggers behind him in her too-high heels?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heaven is a place on Earth</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/heaven-is-a-place-on-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 11:49:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/heaven-is-a-place-on-earth/</guid>
      <description>Early in his new novel This Is Your Life, Harriet Chance!, Jonathan Evison makes an artistic decision that’s sure to divide his readership. It’s on page 14, at the beginning of the book’s fifth chapter, and there’s no way to talk around it, so here we go: Evison sets a scene in heaven, where Harriet Chance’s recently deceased husband, Bernard, gets a dressing-down from a bureaucrat named Charmichael for interfering with the world of the living.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ballad of Rosie the Riveter</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-ballad-of-rosie-the-riveter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 09:50:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-ballad-of-rosie-the-riveter/</guid>
      <description>As we teeter on the cusp of Labor Day weekend, it’s important to remember that women in America are still not an equal part of the workforce. According to whitehouse.gov, full-time working women still earn 78 cents for every dollar men earn, and a typical 25-year-old woman makes $5,000 less per year than a typical man of the same age. It’s interesting to note that those figures are from the same White House where President Obama signed his very first bill, the Lilly Ledbetter Fair Pay Act, into law in January of 2009.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The women problem</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-women-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 12:03:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-women-problem/</guid>
      <description>Let’s say it together now, with the requisite air quotes and eye rolls: “women’s fiction.” All the expected arguments have been made about why the categorization is useless at best, offensive at worst. As Meg Wolitzer noted in the New York Times Book Review last weekend, while this piece was in production, “Bringing up the women’s question — I mean the women’s fiction question — is not unlike mentioning the national debt at a dinner party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pronouns in space</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/pronouns-in-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 12:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/pronouns-in-space/</guid>
      <description>Imagine my delight when the first three pages of Ann Leckie’s Ancillary Justice boggled me with pronouns. They’re all female: she and her; no he, no him. This Elizabeth Moon-like space opera with big ships and engineering settings inhabits a new conceptual landscape, but is it simply a local effect? Ursula Le Guin’s The Left Hand of Darkness (1969) uses ambi-sexual characters to question sexual determination, but the male-female dyad is still the basis for that society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Seattle of your nightmares</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-seattle-of-your-nightmares/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-seattle-of-your-nightmares/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this month, at a progressive rally in downtown Seattle, I watched from across the street as hundreds of allegedly liberal Seattleites booed the suggestion that Black Lives Matter. I saw a middle-aged preppy married couple raise their middle fingers in the air during a moment of silence in memory of a young black man who was killed by police officer. I saw angry white grandmothers beg officers to arrest the two young black women who took the stage, and I heard a small group of hip Capitol Hill dudes, horrifyingly, chant “tase those cunts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun, food, and fear: Farley Mowat and the lessons of Never Cry Wolf</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/fun-food-and-fear-farley-mowat-and-the-lessons-of-never-cry-wolf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 12:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/fun-food-and-fear-farley-mowat-and-the-lessons-of-never-cry-wolf/</guid>
      <description>Being an arachnophobe is popular. It seems to be completely within the realm of reason and decency to severely panic at the sight of a spider of any size. Adult human beings will recount stories of their terror without a hint of shame — sometimes it even seems they do so with pride. While some may capture the spider under a glass, barricade it within using a sheet of paper, and escort it outside, it can be safely assumed that every year millions of spiders are instead crushed upon sight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A cruel mistress</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-cruel-mistress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 12:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/a-cruel-mistress/</guid>
      <description>As an object, Hausfrau is unprepossessing. It eschews visual hallmarks of literary seriousness, by which I mostly mean, it looks girly. The dust jacket invites one to wrinkle her nose at its ingratiating spray of pink and purple roses floating atop a metallic plane, which, combined with the title, suggest the novel might be slumming it in the genre ghetto known as Female Complaint. And at a measly 300-ish pages, it lacks the heft of, say, the Victorians, whose prolixity goes some way with a species of modern reader toward atoning for their trivial concerns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bureaucracy now</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/bureaucracy-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 11:57:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/bureaucracy-now/</guid>
      <description>Here’s what I love about absurdism in literature: It’s a fun way to discuss the terrible things in life. Helen Phillips’s short and propulsive debut novel, The Beautiful Bureaucrat, is a gorgeous example of the stark and spare absurdist genre, a place most gorgeously inhabited by the Russian greats (Zamyatin, Bulgakov, Nabokov). There’s a love story here as big and shadowy as the one in Master and Margarita; there’s also a deft skewering of the American job market that parallels the helplessness within Invitation to a Beheading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OMG Gutenberg</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/omg-gutenberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/omg-gutenberg/</guid>
      <description>A friend who works at the Library of Congress occasionally gets called on to give tours to visiting school groups. The kids respond like most kids would at a government institution: long, bored faces. Not even the gilded grandeur of the building holds much sway.
He takes them to the Gutenberg Bible, laying prone in a glass case, opened to whatever page the curator deemed worthy. This is one of the finest existing copies of the rarest, most valuable book in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s one more American death, give or take?</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/whats-one-more-american-death-give-or-take/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 11:53:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/whats-one-more-american-death-give-or-take/</guid>
      <description>Vendetta, the new book by Seattle Times writer James Neff, begins on the day that many have characterized as the moment when America lost its innocence. Attorney General Robert Kennedy has just enjoyed a picnic lunch on an unseasonably warm November day in Washington DC. Teamsters president Jimmy Hoffa is finishing a meal in a Miami restaurant. Both men are approached with news: President John F. Kennedy has been shot; he’s likely either dead or is about to die.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Picking wires from a bowl of noodles</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/picking-wires-from-a-bowl-of-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/picking-wires-from-a-bowl-of-noodles/</guid>
      <description>Fantagraphics has one of the best design departments in the history of publishing. Their willingness to work the form to the content, rather than the other way around, pays great dividends for book lovers. Often overlooked because the content they are publishing is super-graphic in of itself (comics), their design is eye-catching and functional, while often elevating the text; their materials, paper, binding, and just the feel of their books in your hand is always considered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Although of course you end up being played by Jesse Eisenberg in the movie</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/although-of-course-you-end-up-being-played-by-jesse-eisenberg-in-the-movie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 23:18:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/although-of-course-you-end-up-being-played-by-jesse-eisenberg-in-the-movie/</guid>
      <description>Five years ago, I reviewed David Lipsky’s book Although of Course You End Up Becoming Yourself: A Road Trip with David Foster Wallace. It’s an account, published just a year or so after Wallace’s death, of Lipsky’s days-long Rolling Stone interview with Wallace at the end of his Infinite Jest reading tour. Here’s the nut of the review:
Unfortunately, it&#39;s a bad book, a mass of Lipsky&#39;s notes and personal recollections that he never successfully structured into something useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The last of the big game hunters</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-last-of-the-big-game-hunters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 11:50:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-last-of-the-big-game-hunters/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve spent any amount of time on the internet in the last week or so, you know that Dr. Walter Palmer, a dentist from Minnesota, shot and killed a celebrity lion named Cecil on July 1st of this year in Zimbabwe. Palmer’s actions inspired the internet to recoil in outrage; he was doxxed almost immediately and had to go into hiding when people began plastering the front of his business with shaming messages and threats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sometimes you do the job and sometimes the job does you</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/sometimes-you-do-the-job-and-sometimes-the-job-does-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 09:49:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/sometimes-you-do-the-job-and-sometimes-the-job-does-you/</guid>
      <description>Webcomics are great, but minicomics are satisfying in a way that webcomics will never be able to duplicate. A hand-folded minicomic, especially one still warm from the photocopier, is as intimate and organic as a handwritten letter from a good friend. You can understand why cartoonists made the move from minicomics to webcomics — unlimited distribution, no paper cuts — but you can also understand why some artists still prefer working with ink and paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who gawks at the Gawkers?</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/who-gawks-at-the-gawkers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 07:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/who-gawks-at-the-gawkers/</guid>
      <description>For anyone who’s ever started a publication of any sort — from a magazine to a blog to a newspaper — this scene from Citizen Kane should be required viewing:
 Charles Foster Kane’s promise to his readers, his “Declaration of Principles,” is something every publisher should emulate. They shouldn’t copy Kane’s declaration (“I will provide the people of this city with a daily paper that will tell all the news honestly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You, specifically, should be a feminist</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/you-specifically-should-be-a-feminist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 11:06:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/you-specifically-should-be-a-feminist/</guid>
      <description>Specificity is the key for understanding broader truths. It’s only when we really drill down on a subject that we uncover metaphors that apply to other situations. To a lazy thinker, a rock is just a rock. To a geologist, a rock is a gateway to understanding the world, a subject dense with hidden secrets that affect everything else on earth.
In her book We Should All Be Feminists, Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie digs into the idea of feminism and she uncovers some realizations that simply should not be as surprising as they are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seattle and Seattle and Seattle</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/seattle-and-seattle-and-seattle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 20:03:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/seattle-and-seattle-and-seattle/</guid>
      <description>Private detective Peter Bragg is driving from Bellingham to Seattle. He’s working on a particularly tricky case — an old friend, an affable writer of boring technical articles, has had his life threatened for mysterious reasons — and at every turn Bragg’s past confronts him. He’s far away from his home in San Francisco, his ex-wife is putting the moves on him, and his own childhood keeps creeping into his peripheral vision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tolstoy&#39;s unhappy family moves to the Northwest</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/tolstoys-unhappy-family-moves-to-the-northwest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 23:44:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/tolstoys-unhappy-family-moves-to-the-northwest/</guid>
      <description>The famous opening sentence of Anna Karenina — &amp;rdquo;Happy families are all alike; each unhappy family is unhappy in its own way” — has been overused to the point of meaninglessness, like a word spoken aloud again and again until it becomes an oddity, stripped of its definition and reduced to a few ugly, alien syllables. The sentence is now a cliche that many people interpret as a license to spray their dysfunctional family history everywhere, in the form of memoir and Facebook post and standup routine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The sound of one mouth talking</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-sound-of-one-mouth-talking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 14:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-sound-of-one-mouth-talking/</guid>
      <description>Is literature a conversation or a monologue? Is it possible that the majority of all conversations are just twinned monologues, skating by the ears of their intended targets and firing off into the void in opposite directions? Nearly everyone has been seated in a restaurant near an awkward first date where the conversation, despite both participants’ best efforts, ranges more toward masturbation than copulation. But what if that scenario is the norm, rather than an awkward rarity?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The perpetual naked lunch of Starvation Mode</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-perpetual-naked-lunch-of-starvation-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 23:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-perpetual-naked-lunch-of-starvation-mode/</guid>
      <description>![Elissa Washuta at Hugo House, July 1, 2005](/webhook-uploads/1435818070982/elissawashuta.jpg)
“My eating has been disordered for as long as I can remember,” Elissa Washuta said last night by way of introduction at the launch party for her second memoir, Starvation Mode. The Hugo House was sweltering, but the audience focused on every single word with a surprising acuity. It’s usually hard to get audiences at July readings to focus on anything more than a dirty joke, but Washuta speaks with such intensity that even the sweatiest, most overdressed person in the room — hi there — couldn’t allow his attention to drift if he wanted to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sticking the landing</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/sticking-the-landing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 09:26:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/sticking-the-landing/</guid>
      <description>It is taken as accepted knowledge that Neal Stephenson writes dissatisfying endings to his books. I mentioned to an internet chat room I was reading Seveneves, and this was brought up four times by four separate people. For an insult, it lays bare a tremendous compliment: only a widely read author could inspire such a trope or cliche. It’s a signifier of prestige, in its own way.
It also shows what type of people are reading you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case against Ayn Rand</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-case-against-ayn-rand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 17:09:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/the-case-against-ayn-rand/</guid>
      <description>“[Ayn] Rand’s fans are rarely the sort of intrepid, self-reliant, go-it-alone entrepreneurial heroes she writes about,” Michael Goodwin explains in the introduction to Darryl Cunningham’s new graphic novel The Age of Selfishness. Goodwin continues:
Rather, they’ve typically spent their lives in the comfortable embrace of large institutions, going from school to university to corporation, or from think tank to government and back again. If Paul Ryan—a government bureaucrat if ever there was one—loves reading about [*Atlas Shrugged* protagonists] John Galt and Hank Rearden, it’s because he doesn’t resemble them at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traveling light</title>
      <link>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/traveling-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 23:06:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://seattlereviewofbooks.com/reviews/traveling-light/</guid>
      <description>The old joke goes that the first book Johannes Gutenberg published on his brand-new press was the Bible, but the second book he published was about the death of the publishing industry. Like most of the jokes old booksellers tell one another to pass the time, it’s not funny but it’s got a sick tinge of truth to it; my two decades in the book business as a bookseller and a critic has spanned at least five distinct deaths of the publishing industry.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>